<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COMM-260 Quant Methods &amp; Data Viz (Spring 2019)</title>
    <description>Final projects from students in Quantitative Methods &amp; Data Visualization at American University Spring 2019.  
</description>
    <link>http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 16:00:50 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 16:00:50 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.5</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Metropolitan Police Stop and Frisk: Unsuccessful?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A 10-year-old &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nbcwashington.com/news/local/DC-Attorney-General-10-Year-Old-Boy-Handcuffed-by-Police-Totally-Innocent-508179501.html&quot;&gt;black child was taken from the sidewalk&lt;/a&gt; and handcuffed into police custody earlier this month in Washington, D.C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This followed a report that three boys robbed a young man of his wallet in the district’s northeast quadrant. The Metropolitan Police Department positively identified the 10-year-old boy with description of one of the attackers, which lead them to stop and detain him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Videos of the incident gained over two million views on Twitter prompting retweets and comments about his calm and compliant demeanor and the lack of reason from the police officers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote class=&quot;twitter-tweet&quot; data-lang=&quot;en&quot;&gt;&lt;p lang=&quot;en&quot; dir=&quot;ltr&quot;&gt;🚨 Police falsely arrested a 10 year old and put him in handcuffs : Washington, D.C.&amp;#39;s attorney general says he is &amp;quot;totally innocent&amp;quot; and will not be charged. Now he has nightmares and can’t sleep &lt;a href=&quot;https://t.co/Ng2ItgWwYj&quot;&gt;pic.twitter.com/Ng2ItgWwYj&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&amp;mdash; GG 🧚🏽‍♂️💫🍑 (@ggqt3) &lt;a href=&quot;https://twitter.com/ggqt3/status/1116052505199292416?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw&quot;&gt;April 10, 2019&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;script async=&quot;&quot; src=&quot;https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js&quot; charset=&quot;utf-8&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Later, D.C. Attorney General Karl Racine said the boy was “totally innocent” after reviewing surveillance footage. Chaquitta Williams, the boy’s mother, shared with the media that the boy was suffering from harmful psychological effects following his stop and detainment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Fourth Amendment defends the Americans’ right to be secure in their persons and houses without searches, seizures or arbitrary arrests.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stop and frisk is defined by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.law.cornell.edu/wex/terry_stop_stop_and_frisk&quot;&gt;Cornell Legal Information Institute&lt;/a&gt; as a “brief, non-intrusive police stop of a suspect.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the average age of D.C. citizens stopped in 2018 was 30 years old, 748 juveniles were stopped: 663 were black, and 57 were white, based on Metropolitan Police Department  data. This means that 93% of children under 18 who are stopped by police are minorities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Davone King, 19, was a juvenile in 2016 when he had his first interaction with the police. King walking home from Phelps Architecture, Construction, and Engineering High School in northeast D.C. when eight police officers in bulletproof vests jumped out of unmarked cars and told him not to move.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They all got their hands on their guns already,” King recounted. “Like if I run, do I really want to get shot in the back?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;King and his three friends were searched in their school uniforms and never told why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“No one wrote anything down, they just came up and searched everybody…said they’re checking for guns,” King said. “You’re not supposed to be able to do that.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Reasonable suspicion for a stop does not automatically provide the basis for a pat down,” according to a prepared statement by the Metropolitan Police Department’s Press Office. “[A] set of facts, circumstances, or reliable information that would lead a reasonable and prudent police officer to believe that a crime has been committed, or is about to be committed, and that a certain person committed it.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an interview on Monday, King said “if you like the police, something is wrong with you.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;DC Councilmember Brianne Nadeau &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/opinions/localopinions/end-stop-and-frisk-in-dc/2019/02/14/cdd59c2c-2fab-11e9-8ad3-9a5b113ecd3c_story.html?utm_term=.ff89bb182228&quot;&gt;wrote an essay&lt;/a&gt; for the Washington Post in February that focused on her frustration with the lack of connection between community policing and community safety in Ward 1 as a result of stop and frisk.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Michael Abate, 20, never questioned the authority of police growing up in suburban Maryland. He was raised to recognize a connection between police officers and safety. When he came to the district to attend college, however, he had his first negative encounters with law enforcement. “While I was riding in my friend’s car, Metropolitan Police stopped [us] for relatively no reason,” said Abate. “Obviously when it’s a car full of black men, we’re kind of f***ed in the situation.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The DC Office of Police Complaints data shows that 89% of reported uses of force by MPD officers in 2017 involved black subjects; the most common officer-subject pairing was white officers using force on black subjects, which accounted for 44% of all reported uses of force.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/zXILS80IyyU&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allow=&quot;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017, a 40-year-old black and southeast D.C. resident, M.B. Cottingham, was subjected to a forceful patdown by Metropolitan Police. &lt;a href=&quot;https://wamu.org/story/18/12/06/settlement-reached-with-d-c-police-after-inappropriate-touching-during-stop-and-frisk/&quot;&gt;WAMU shared a quote&lt;/a&gt; from Cottingham:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“If I didn’t have the video, no one would believe me,” he says. “The video speaks for itself. It shows the truth … the video shows everything I say was the truth.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Regardless of whether force was used in a search, 83% of stop-and-frisks were of black residents, who make up 47% of the DC population&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flourish-embed&quot; data-src=&quot;visualisation/334631&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Washington is not the only city that disproportionately conducts random searches on black populations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Black stops per capita&quot; aria-label=&quot;Split Bars&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-VRg5E&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/VRg5E/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;199&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to maps analyzing police stop data, the three regions in D.C. with highest recorded stops of black citizens occur in census tracts 44, 58 and 73.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;African American Stops by District&quot; aria-label=&quot;USA district of columbia census tracts choropleth map&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-jpMq5&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/jpMq5/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://censusreporter.org/profiles/14000US11001004400-census-tract-44-district-of-columbia-dc/&quot;&gt;Tract 44&lt;/a&gt; surrounds the U Street Metro Station and the area near Howard University, a historically black university in D.C. According to Census Reporter, the population in that area is 67% white. &lt;a href=&quot;https://censusreporter.org/profiles/14000US11001005800-census-tract-58-district-of-columbia-dc/&quot;&gt;Tract 58&lt;/a&gt; covers the area between Lafayette Square and Chinatown, which Census Reporter shows as 61% white. &lt;a href=&quot;https://censusreporter.org/profiles/14000US11001007304-census-tract-7304-district-of-columbia-dc/&quot;&gt;Tract 73&lt;/a&gt; is near the Congress Heights Metro Station in southeast D.C. and is demographically 91% black.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Neighborhood Engagement Achieves Results (NEAR) Act was implemented by the D.C. Council in 2016 to train police to be unbiased. Mayor Muriel Bowser fully funded all 20 provisions of the NEAR Act when it was implemented. In 2017, she &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.scribd.com/document/378019865/B22-0754-Errata-Letter2&quot;&gt;wrote a letter&lt;/a&gt; to the DC Council Chairman in which she said $300,000 should be added to the MPD budget for NEAR Act implementation and data collection funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the high quantity of stop and frisks in suspicious circumstances, in an effort to prevent crimes, the rate of violent crimes should be decreasing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Annual Homicide Count in DC&quot; aria-label=&quot;Interactive area chart&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/QWKgj/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, there has been an overall increase in homicides since 2016 when the act to lessen police bias was put into place. The right people are being patted down. Perhaps the funding will be redirected in the future to specifically train Metropolitan Police Department units in areas where the stop counts are not racially disproportionate.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 06:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/dc-stop-and-frisk/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/dc-stop-and-frisk/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>How Safe is American University? Deciphering AUPD’s Daily Crime Log</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As required by law, American University provides crime statistics by releasing an annual security report and by updating a daily crime log that details violations happening on campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/campus1.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From analyzing the data within the daily crime logs provided by the American University Police Department, it is evident that alcohol violations are the most common crime occurring on campus. In addition, even when adjusted for per capita rates, the residence halls have the highest level of crimes. Cases of sexual assault at American University increased in the wake of national coverage of the #MeToo movement. American University also has high rates of alcohol, drug, and sexual assault violations compared to other colleges within the D.C. area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the #MeToo movement and the opioid epidemic happening on a national scale, and a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.adl.org/resources/reports/2017-audit-of-anti-semitic-incidents&quot;&gt;rise in bias-related incidents on college campuses&lt;/a&gt;, there has been increased scrutiny of the crime statistics for universities. At the same time, these logs and reports are not easily accessible. This is problematic when many American University students are unaware of the crimes taking place on and around campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Student Perspective on the General Trend of AU Crimes&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American University students believe that they live on a safe college campus. Jacob Louis, a sophomore, said that he felt safe most of the time and it only sometimes gets “weird at night.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The American University Police Department (AUPD) enforces safety on campus. It is composed of over &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.american.edu/police/&quot;&gt;60 police officers&lt;/a&gt;, has over 600 cameras that survey the campus, and protects an undergraduate population of &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.usnews.com/best-colleges/american-university-1434&quot;&gt;more than 8,000 students&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the analysis of the daily crime logs provided by the university, 2,531 crimes happened between July 10th, 2015 and March 31st, 2019. The average crime rate was less than one crime per day. This is consistent with students reporting that they felt safe on American University’s campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to best understand the crimes that occur, it is necessary to view the general trend of crime rates over a full year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/campus2.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were three full academic years reported: 2016, 2017, and 2018. Before the year 2015, the US Department of Education did not collect individual statistics for rape, fondling, incest, and statutory rape, so this article only includes the years 2015 through 2019. The year 2016 had the highest number of crimes with 796 violations in the course of one year. In these three years, there is a visible trend of crimes decreasing in July and then rising in August through October. This would coincide with students going home for the summer and then returning to American University for the fall semester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are the number of crimes reported by semester. When looking at the data provided, the spring semester typically has a higher average crime rate than the fall semester. The spring has an average of 335 crimes while the fall has an average of 296 crimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/campus3.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Crime Log Explanation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every calendar year, American University releases two different reports: the Annual Security Report and the daily crime log. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.american.edu/finance/publicsafety/upload/2017-Annual-Security[-Report.pdf&quot;&gt;The American University Annual Security Report&lt;/a&gt; is a lengthy booklet that contains all information they must report to abide by the Jeanne Clery Disclosure of Campus Security Policy and Campus Crime Statistics Act] (https://ifap.ed.gov/eannouncements/attachments/HandbookforCampusSafetyandSecurityReporting.pdf) (also known as the Clery Act). This report is a general synopsis of crimes over a calendar year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Clery Act is a federal statute that requires colleges and universities that receive federal financial aid programs to maintain and disclose crimes on campus. This act requires that colleges disclose specific crimes that are defined on the United States Department of Education website and report it to the federal agency. The crimes that must be reported and recorded include: murder/ non-negligent manslaughter, negligent manslaughter, rape, fondling, incest, statutory rape, robbery, aggravated assault, burglary, motor vehicle theft, arson, hate crimes, domestic violence, dating violence, stalking, weapon possession, drug abuse violations, and liquor law violations. Domestic violence, dating violence, and stalking are all under a subcategory called VAWA offenses. Under the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ifap.ed.gov/eannouncements/attachments/HandbookforCampusSafetyandSecurityReporting.pdf&quot;&gt;Hierarchy Rule&lt;/a&gt; within the guidelines of the Clery Act, if more than one criminal offense was committed during a single incident, the institution only counts the most severe offense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The daily crime log provides detailed statistics of crimes per day per academic year. None of the students interviewed had heard of the daily crime log, but it was a pretty small sample. They said that they received most of their information about crimes from AU text alerts and emails. This is where the data that the daily crime log provides is essential, as the American University Police Department only discloses crucial offenses that threaten the safety of many students in their text alerts and emails.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what the crime log looks like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/campus4.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around 45% of the crimes reported occur outside of the main campus. Students, AUPD, and neighbors of AU can report crimes. At the same time, the majority of crimes reported by AUPD happen within American University’s Tenleytown campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the things that Shannon Dargan, a junior, explained is that American University is an “open campus.” This means that AU and non-AU students, staff and faculty can enter the administrative buildings and the campus during regular working hours without security clearance.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dargan said, “It’s pretty open. For evidence, you can see the hate crimes that have taken place in the past, and I think the safety depends on honestly who you are as a student on this campus.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ava Schulte, a sophomore, also brought up AU’s status as an open campus as a reason for crime. She said, “It is a really open campus. Someone can easily come on here.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;AU-Centered Crimes and Conduct&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On American University’s campus, the majority of crimes happen within the confines of the residence halls. Within the top nine locations of campus crimes, the majority of them are residence halls: Anderson Hall, Letts Hall, Leonard Hall, Centennial Hall, Cassell Hall, McDowell Hall, and Hughes Hall. However, within the top four locations on campus are the three residence halls where the majority of freshman live: Anderson Hall, Letts Hall, and Centennial Hall.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Top Nine Locations of Crimes on American University's Tenleytown Campus&quot; aria-label=&quot;Locator Maps&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-VMO3q&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/VMO3q/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;553&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Residence halls vary in terms of the size of their populations. In order to adjust for this, the rates were altered by the average number of students living within the hall. Director of Housing, Christopher Silva, provided the average number of students living within each of the residence halls. However, even when calculating the per capita rates, Anderson Hall, the freshman dorm with the largest number of residents, still had the highest rate of crimes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Rate of Crimes per 100 People in Residence Halls &quot; aria-label=&quot;Stacked Bars&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-oY3SK&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/oY3SK/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;412&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As for the students’ input on what was the most common crime, none of them could agree. Angelina, a sophomore, said, “Maybe people stealing things, petty things like laptops, things like that.” Dargan said, “Juuling. I know we’re technically a smoke-free campus.” When it comes to the crimes reported on campus, alcohol violations trump the other crimes reported by AUPD in sheer size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Top 10 Crimes Reported at American University&quot; aria-label=&quot;Bar Chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-RRtvJ&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/RRtvJ/3/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;485&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alcohol violations make up 40% of the crimes reported. According to the Health Promotion and Advocacy Center (HPAC), substance use at American University is consistently higher than the national average. In self-reported surveys conducted by HPAC, 76% of students &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.american.edu/ocl/promote-health/upload/Alcohol-PDF.pdf&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; using alcohol compared to 60% of college students between the ages of 18-22 &lt;a href=&quot;https://pubs.niaaa.nih.gov/publications/CollegeFactSheet/CollegeFactSheet.pdf&quot;&gt;nationwide&lt;/a&gt;. At AU, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.american.edu/ocl/promote-health/upload/Marijuana-PDF.pdf&quot;&gt;26%&lt;/a&gt; of students report using cannabis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students within the AU community seem to recognize this reality. When Callie Forseley learned that alcohol violations were the number one crime reported by AUPD, she said, “Oh that makes sense. Once you’re in college and you’re far away from your parents, people feel like they can drink and do shit. And they’re not smart about it and they get caught.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Peter Close, a sophomore, said that he believed that the highest crimes could be attributed to drug or alcohol violations. He said, “AU’s alcohol policies are pretty stringent, and people are often caught with that.” Close said he knew someone on his floor who, “had his entire pot-selling ring shut down on campus and then he was expelled.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are specific policies and programs that American University is using to remediate the number of crimes within the residence hall complexes. Director Silva said, “All incoming students must complete an online educational program called AlcoholEdu” which is a two-part course which “provides education on awareness training, alcohol abuse prevention, and safe drinking tips for college-aged students.” In addition, he said, incoming students “are all required to go through the Empower AU program” which “is a 90-minute consent education and communication training, and covers a section on alcohol use – standard drink sizes, harm reduction tips, effects of alcohol on body/brain, and relationship between alcohol and consent.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When certain crimes occur and violate rights, the conduct council, AUPD, and HPAC are in charge of resolving the issue with the student, but it depends on the crime and the violations. For example, the student conduct council only referred 26% of the crimes that occur on campus. The student conduct council did not respond for a comment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Number of Incidents of Sexual Assault and Abuse at American University&quot; aria-label=&quot;Interactive line chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-fbZiK&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/fbZiK/2/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Alongside alcohol violations, we examined sexual assault cases. This includes all forms of sexual violence within the daily crime log; sexual assault, rape, fondling, sexual abuse and sexual offenses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are some months where sexual assault is unreported, but at the same time, they can peak at 12 sexual assaults in one month. From this data, it is clear that sexual assault and abuse case reports increased in the wake of the #MeToo movement. Two instances included the sexual assault accusations against Harvey Weinstein and the uncovering of Dr. Christine Ford’s allegations. Ultimately, some sexual assault cases are reported to AUPD, but they do not express the total number of cases that go unreported or cases reported to other administrative resources like OASIS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A Title IX Program Officer at American University, Regina Curran, said, “the daily crime log is intended to reflect what is reported to the University Police.” This means sexual assaults do not have to be added to the statistics when it happens to an AU student off-campus or does not fit within the Clery Act definitions. This lowers the amount of data that is published. Curran agrees that even in the past few years with the #MeToo movement there have been more people coming forward and speaking up, but sexual assaults remain primarily underreported, even though the university has tried to make their resources more accessible to students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;AU in the context of DC and its schools&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When initially examining the daily crime log, many report numbers were absent. This seemed to demonstrate that the crimes are not as detailed or that AUPD might be under-reporting the crimes occurring on campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Assistant Vice President of the University Police Services and Emergency Management Phillip Morse said, “nothing is hidden.” He explained that the crime log goes beyond what is required of American University but also does not feature crimes that are crucial to the security and safety of students like welfare checks or traffic violations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After examining American University’s substance violations and sexual assaults individually, we compared AU to other college campuses in D.C. to see if crimes are an issue elsewhere. From 2015 to 2017, American University had a total of 1,645 substance violations that either resulted in arrests or disciplinary actions. Out of these colleges, American University has the third largest total enrollment with 13,858 in 2017. George Washington University had the highest enrollment in 2017 followed by Georgetown University with the second largest enrollment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Rate of Substance Violations for DC Colleges between 2015-2017 Per 1,000 Students&quot; aria-label=&quot;Stacked Bars&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-EixYw&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/EixYw/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;256&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As evident from the chart above, Catholic University of America has the highest rate of substance use violations per capita, with American University in second place. This demonstrates that American University is one of the leading schools in the District for substance violations, even though it does not have a high enrollment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We also examined sexual assaults to these other DC colleges, and American had the second most sexual assaults on campus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Rate of Sexual Assaults of DC Colleges from 2015-2017 Per 1,000 Students&quot; aria-label=&quot;Bar Chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-Uh6oe&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/Uh6oe/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;226&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though Title IX officer Curran believes that the AU campus is relatively safe due to its location in the more suburban area of DC, she said, “[the ages of] 18 to 24 is the highest risk time of your life for sexual violence, whether you go to college or not.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“So, are we relatively safe? Yes. Is college a risky time for sexual violence? Also yes,” said Curran.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is evident that certain crimes are happening more than others including alcohol violations, theft and drug violations. In response to the number of alcohol violations reported, Director Silva said that he could not identify whether American University’s rates were average, but he said, “Every campus is unique.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the same time, these are the crimes that have been reported to the American University Police Department or students that have been caught violating the conduct code. There are crimes on campus that still go unreported and unseen; sexual assaults where students are afraid to come forward or students are secretly sneaking substances.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While students are aware of the substance use on campus, they do not have an accurate portrayal of how often these crimes are happening.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 05:06:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/au-campus-safety/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/au-campus-safety/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>As the District’s White Population Increases, Gay and Lesbian Bars Rapidly Decrease</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Washington, D.C.— Over the last 20 years, D.C. residents have noticed a significant change in their neighborhood nightlife. While some may see the boom in new restaurants and bars as evidence that nightlife is thriving, those who have lived here longer know better.
Ebone Bell, founder and editor of Tagg magazine, grew up in the D.C. area and has lived in Southeast, D.C. for the last few years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What’s sad is we barely have any bars,” said Bell in an interview. “I talk to neighbors and we’re all like ‘it would be nice to have something,’ I don’t even care if its gay or not. I just want to be able to walk into something instead of having to go down to H St, and nothing on H St is a gay bar- they may have a gay owner or people that go in there that are gay but there is not a designated gay bar on H St. I literally have to go downtown to Northwest.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This trend is indicative of a larger problem in the District- over the last 20 years, gentrification of D.C. neighborhoods has led to an overall increase in the opening of bars and clubs, but it has simultaneously lead to an increase in the closure of many of the District’s traditionally lesbian and gay bars. Some attribute it to the popularity of online dating apps and queer pop-up parties, and others say it shows progress. More and more non-LGBTQ nightlife venues are opening up their spaces to the LGBTQ community for queer events. However, others believe in the importance of queer-centered spaces and their rich histories in the District that are being destroyed as neighborhoods become whiter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although the issue received wider attention last month with the unexpected closing of Cobalt, a mainstay of gay D.C. nightlife since 1999, and Town DanceBoutique last year, this problem is not new.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“D.C. historically has had so many places that served and were spaces for the black queer community,” said Kate Rabinowitz, a reporter for the Washington Post.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In her article &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dcpolicycenter.org/publications/history-d-c-prides-places-spaces/&quot;&gt;“A Timeline of LGBTQ places and spaces in D.C,”&lt;/a&gt; she notes how in the 1970s, DuPont Circle, Barracks Row and South Capitol Street became known for their gay and lesbian nightlife. These places were not just important spaces to drink and party, but they were centers of grassroots organizing and activism. But from the 1970s, the number of new gay bars opening steadily declined. Since 2000, these closures have rapidly increased.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Closed LGBTQ D.C. Bars by Tract Since 2000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe title=&quot;Closed Gay and Lesbian D.C. Bars by Tract Since 2000&quot; aria-label=&quot;USA district of columbia census tracts Symbol map&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-IV1IO&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/IV1IO/2/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Phase One, one of the oldest lesbian bars in the country, opened in 1970 on Barracks Row and closed in February of 2016. It is now a gym, next to a Cava. In 1957, Nob Hill, the Districts first gay bar for African Americans, opened in Columbia Heights. It was a space for gay, black men excluded from D.C. queer nightlife at the time, and it remained that way until it closed in 2004. The space was repurposed into the Wonderland Ballroom, which is not an LGBTQ bar, although every first Thursday of the month they throw a gay dance party. Most other spaces were torn down and became either restaurants, bars, or apartments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of the 47 gay and lesbian bars and clubs that closed since 2000, 23% were repurposed into non-LGBTQ bars and 21% became apartments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;** Repurposed Closed Gay and Lesbian Bars After 2000 **&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flourish-embed&quot; data-src=&quot;visualisation/334224&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many new bar and restaurant owners see this as a good thing in terms of the city’s economic development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Navy Yard didn’t even exist 10 years ago or even really the Shaw area wasn’t incredibly built up,” said Heidi Minora, general manager of LGBTQ friendly restaurant Commissary in Logan Circle. “There were parts of 14th St that people didn’t even go to or walk down. There was a broke down laundromat that was there for like 10 years that never had anyone in it…yes it is sad that older buildings that have been there for a long time are getting torn down and turned into other spaces, but abandoned buildings are not good for the neighborhood.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, the truth is that these places did exist and people did go there. Gentrification took away spaces for the original communities that had lived in these neighborhoods for a while, largely spaces for people of color, places they could afford, they could hang out, and spaces they were safe in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While writing another &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.dcpolicycenter.org/publications/d-c-nightlife-churn/&quot;&gt;article&lt;/a&gt; on D.C. nightlife, Rabinowitz noticed the data didn’t tell the full story. Some areas, especially Navy Yard, looked entirely new to the nightlife scene but that was because the starting point of the data did not go back far enough. Specifically, in 2006, a number of historic gay and lesbian establishments in Southeast were destroyed to build that Nationals Ballpark Stadium. Many don’t know this history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Percent Point Difference of White Population per Tract from 2010 to 2017&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe title=&quot;Percent Point Difference of White Population per Tract from 2010 to 2017&quot; aria-label=&quot;USA district of columbia census tracts choropleth map&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-ppOQ7&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/ppOQ7/3/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 2010 to 2017, Navy Yard saw a 33.46 percent point difference in its white population, the second highest percent point difference out of all tracts. That means its white population grew significantly in five years. This year, Navy Yard was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wusa9.com/article/news/local/dc/dc-is-the-most-gentrified-city-navy-yard-is-its-most-gentrified-neighborhood/65-23d15069-8980-482e-baea-37949da9c816&quot;&gt;listed&lt;/a&gt;
as D.C.’s most gentrified neighborhood.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Comparing the percent point difference in white people with the number of gay or lesbian bars that have closed since 2000 per neighborhood, the data shows that the Navy Yard tract was the area with the most closures. This number becomes even larger when the neighborhoods directly surrounding it are included in the count.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Percent Point Difference of Whites from 2010 to 2017 and Number of Lesbian/Gay Bars Closed Per D.C. Census Tract Since 2000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Percent Point Difference of Whites from 2010 to 2017 and Number of Lesbian/Gay Bars Closed Per D.C. Census Tract Since 2000&quot; aria-label=&quot;Scatter Plot&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-oCNwr&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/oCNwr/3/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The tracts that make up DuPont Circle showed an increase in their white population and a total of twelve gay bars closures since 2000. Overall, there was a high concentration of closures in the DuPont Circle, Logan Circle, and U St. neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Number per Tract of Closed Lesbian and Gay Bars Since 2000&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe title=&quot;Number per Tract of Closed Lesbian and Gay Bars Since 2000&quot; aria-label=&quot;USA district of columbia census tracts choropleth map&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-4Aen4&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/4Aen4/3/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gay spaces that are not taken over by the government like the ones in Navy Yard in 2006 are still subject to closure as increasing prices in gentrified neighborhoods make rent prices for some bar and club owners unaffordable, or increasing drink prices make the bars and clubs unaffordable to the populations they once depended on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Town DanceBoutique, the largest gay club in the District, sold last year for $25 million. In the past 10 years, the Shaw/U St. area where it was located has turned into a millennial nightlife mecca. Millennials now make up &lt;a href=&quot;https://planning.dc.gov/sites/default/files/dc/sites/op/page_content/attachments/Millennials%20Demographic%20Characteristics%20DC%20vs%20US.pdf&quot;&gt;35%&lt;/a&gt; of D.C.’s population, and white millennials have grown 15% in DC since 1980, despite decreasing nationwide. D.C. is getting younger, whiter, and wealthier, meaning nightlife is really only growing for those who fall into those categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Gentrification is affecting these spaces in another way too- not just displacement, but replacement. An increasing number of straight millennials are taking over gay bars. Nellie’s Sports Bar on U St, for example, is listed as a gay bar but it has simply become another U St. bar for any drunk person, regardless of sexuality, to bar hop too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We can still call 16th or 17th and R, that area, a gayborhood but we really don’t have gayborhoods anymore and that’s because of the mainstream acceptance and a little bit of the gentrification,” said Bell.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For queer womxn of color especially, the lack of nightlife spaces that cater specifically to them has always been an issue. None of the lesbian bars that have opened after 2000 have stayed open for more than a couple of years. To adapt to this, in 2016 a number of queer womxn party promoters began throwing monthly pop-up parties and events in non-LGBTQ spaces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I think gentrification in our own community made us have to create something that’s ours because we are surrounded by everybody that doesn’t look like us,” said Bell. “We go into mainstream bars and sometimes we get harassed, but it’s great to be able to walk into any establishment. However, its comfortable, wonderful, freeing, and safe to walk into a place that is your own where you are surrounded by people who get you and who share the same experiences.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D.C. LGBTQ Nightlife&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flourish-embed&quot; data-src=&quot;visualisation/321102&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bell is hopeful for the future of the two queer womxn bars that opened last year- A League of Her Own in Adams Morgan and XX+ on U St. According to her, spaces like these specifically for queer womxn and queer womxn of color are important because most of D.C.’s gay bars cater to white, cisgender men.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2014, D.C. was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/blogs/local/wp/2014/01/06/the-advocate-says-d-c-is-the-gayest-city-in-america/?utm_term=.8fb4fd3349fc&quot;&gt;listed&lt;/a&gt; as the “Gayest City in America,” but this year it’s made number one on another list: the U.S. city with the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/transportation/2019/03/19/study-dc-has-had-highest-intensity-gentrification-any-us-city/?utm_term=.dfaec2206f83&quot;&gt;“highest intensity”&lt;/a&gt; of gentrification. An influx of white people, among other signifiers of gentrification, correlates with the destruction and replacement of so many historical lesbian and gay spaces, it seems unlikely the District will continue to exist on both of these lists.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 04:10:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/gay-bars-dc-gentrification/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/gay-bars-dc-gentrification/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Why Schools with the Most Funding Have the Most Problems</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;As the first period bell rings at Franklin High School, students run through the halls and in and out of bathrooms. Littering and cursing, they pay no mind to their tardy attendance record. While security and teachers on hall duty would alleviate this issue, the gross understaffing of the building makes this impossible. For Kelly Boyd, a teacher at Franklin High School in Baltimore County, Maryland, this is her daily reality. “When students don’t see the presence of teachers on hall duty (because they are pulled for class coverages), when students don’t see consistent security presence in the hallways (because we don’t have a full-time security officer), and when the grounds and facilities aren’t kept as clean as they could be (because building service is consistently understaffed), it affects the way students see their school as being ‘good’ or ‘bad’,” Boyd says. If Franklin had more funds to pay a larger staff, perhaps the idea that students were getting an education in one of the “better” Baltimore County schools would be more believable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Franklin High School and its parent, the Baltimore County Public School system, are not underfunded. It ranks in the top half of all Maryland schools for total funding per student, and yet is ranked 20th of the 24 county districts, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.schooldigger.com/go/MD/districtrank.aspx&quot;&gt;School Digger&lt;/a&gt; (a website that ranks school districts based on test scores). Boyd suggests this may be due to a poor allocation of funds given to the district. “One of the biggest ways that funding impacts the quality of education at Franklin isn’t in the classroom, but in the areas outside of the classroom. We’ve received many interesting bits of classroom technology in the 8 years that I’ve worked here (students have 1-1 laptops, all classrooms have document cameras and projectors, etc), but in terms of the hallways, bathrooms, and in-between class activities workings, I can see the ways that financial struggles can take a toll.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Delaney Maul, a 9th grader at Franklin, has seen similar patterns. “The quality of bathrooms and many of the textbooks are in really bad condition, the bathrooms are disgusting,” she says.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a common misconception that schools with more problems are schools with less funding and little attention from higher-ups in public education. Counties that are populated with more minority students often seem less resourced and therefore have less fortunate public school options. “Per Pupil” is a figure represented in Maryland Finances and Demographic Information that measures the total funds distributed for one individual student in the county. The funds for this singular student, as well as the school district as a whole, are broken up into local, state and federal allowances. In the case of Maryland public schools, when local funding is particularly low, the state and federal budgets increase accordingly. The maps below depict the differences in local funding and state funding.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Local Per Pupil Funding by County&quot; aria-label=&quot;USA maryland counties choropleth map&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-0y6JQ&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/0y6JQ/3/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;State Per Pupil Funding by County&quot; aria-label=&quot;USA maryland counties choropleth map&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-zPAdx&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/zPAdx/2/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In most cases, the counties with lower local per pupil funding, have higher state per pupil funding. Take Worcester County for example- it has the lowest state funding and the highest local funding. Ideally, this would create equal opportunities between wealthier counties with more resources and impoverished counties with fewer resources. When the local, state and federal per pupil funds of each Maryland county are combined and compared to the percent minority of every county, it is clear that some of the most racially diverse areas receive more money (the correlation between minority percentages and total per student funding is nearly 42%).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Poverty Rates and Total Funds Per Student&quot; aria-label=&quot;Scatter Plot&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-muk3K&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/muk3K/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But funding isn’t the only dimension of resources faced by school districts. And yet, attention is often given to this dimension over other, more crucial resources. Boyd is quoted with saying the following points:
“What sometimes concerns me is the way those funds end up being allocated. When they are tied to test scores and graduation rates, we often see schools teaching to the test in order to try and obtain more funding for at-risk students. Such practices can shift the focus from what students need to what teachers need, and can contribute to student disengagement, which contributes to a really awful feedback cycle of students hating school.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Average Total Funds Spent by Percentage Minority Counties&quot; aria-label=&quot;Bar Chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-eUKFf&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/eUKFf/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;223&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Median Household Income in the Past 12 Months (In 2017 Inflation-adjusted Dollars)&quot; aria-label=&quot;USA maryland counties choropleth map&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-obYLy&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/obYLy/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When ranks and funds are given to schools based solely on test performance, it skews the focus of education. Students from wealthier neighborhoods grow up with more resources and different support systems outside of school, which affects their educational development. While investing in resources that center around curriculum helps school systems rank well, it does not help students with individualized learning needs (work ethic, patience, diligence, etc.).  Diana Spencer, Communications Officer for Baltimore County Schools, said the following of education and poverty levels as it relates to inequity:
“We have succeeded in closing the graduation rate gap between black and white students, but not the achievement gap. The reasons for this are so many – from the multigenerational challenges of being black and brown in this nation (from redlining to the inequities in the justice system), to unconscious bias on the part of teachers (most of whom are young white women), to inequities in health care and early childhood education. Because of the intergenerational poverty and disinvestment in the neighborhoods of Baltimore City, that school system is failing by every measure. We are not. But we, like every other public school system, has a long way to go in achieving equity and helping every student fulfill his or her promise.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Funds don’t alleviate deeper systemic issues. A laptop does not teach a child to learn, and neither does a standardized test. As school districts continue to push toward standardized education as a method to seize funding, they will inherently lose their ability to encourage creativity and excitement about learning. While it is important to offer programs like free or reduced-price lunch, this doesn’t fix the systemic issue- it’s a temporary patch on a leak that is easier than replacing the pipe entirely.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Obviously, we should fund schools equally. But how that funding is used must be considered using more factors than test scores. Students in impoverished neighborhoods have different developmental needs than students growing up in wealthier neighborhoods. Experiences they are surrounded by, opportunities they have available outside of school, and general encouragement to think, learn, and grow inside and outside the classroom differ. While the funds are available, these factors may not be considered in the allocation process of these funds appropriately. Attention not only to test scores and quantitative measures of performance, but qualitative factors in students’ environments is necessary to achieve substantial effective education reform.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 03:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/maryland-school-funding/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/maryland-school-funding/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>District Sees Number of Cyclists collisions Rise </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://wamu.org/story/18/07/19/cyclists-pedestrians-protest-recent-deaths-d-c-streets/&quot;&gt;On&lt;/a&gt; June 23 Malik Habib was out at night, biking around the city to deliver food like the countless other teenagers in the district. Only on that night Habib never made home after his bike caught on a street car rail causing him to move forward onto the path of an incoming charter bus. Habib was rushed to the hospital but died of his injuries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in the past most fatal cyclist accidents are quickly forgotten, this time it was different. In the weeks and months following Habib’s death hundreds of bikers protested in the city by blocking roads and marching on city hall.
Colin Browne, who works for the Washington Area Bikers Association (WABA), an advocacy group that helped organize the protests, believes the outrage should not have surprised officials.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“While we don’t want to blame one department many cyclists in the city have felt for a long time that the city government and DDOT are not doing enough to protect them,” Browne said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As public transportation use has &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cato.org/publications/policy-analysis/charting-public-transits-decline&quot;&gt;declined&lt;/a&gt;, multiple city governments across the country have been struggling to find ways to protect pedestrians and bicyclists. With biking becoming an increasingly popular activity in the U.S., especially for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.bikeleague.org/content/what-can-rise-cycling-tell-us-about-its-future&quot;&gt;young professionals&lt;/a&gt; getting to work, the need to protect bikers has grown as injury and fatality rates increase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the district biking has become more prominent in the city over the last ten years with a number of bike clubs and bike sharing programs being formed. Browne says, the popular Capital Bikeshare, founded in 2010, has provided a “low cost barrier” to getting into biking as customers can rent bikes for only a few dollars.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recent surge in biking can also be &lt;a href=&quot;https://trec.pdx.edu/blog/are-millennials-really-generation-bikes&quot;&gt;attributed&lt;/a&gt; to the district’s expanding young professional population which Derek Hyra, an American University professor on Urban politics, has studied over the past decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Unlike in other cities during the great recession, D.C. saw an increase in its populations with most newcomers being millennials looking for work,” Hyra said.
So, with biking becoming a larger part of the city’s transportation system, advocates like Browne say the district should try and emulate other cities that are more welcoming to bikers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Portland would be a great place to be in terms of allowing safe biking conditions on the road but honestly we would really like to see strides made to bring D.C. closer to Europe,” Browne said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in 2015 that’s exactly what the Bowser administration promised when they announced the &lt;a href=&quot;https://dcist.com/story/15/12/16/vision-zero-1/&quot;&gt;Vision-Zero Initiative&lt;/a&gt; Based off a policy used in Sweden, the plan wants to see all traffic injuries and deaths to reach zero by 2024. It will do this by increasing the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/dr-gridlock/wp/2015/12/10/violate-d-c-traffic-laws-its-gonna-cost-you-a-lot/?utm_term=.c1fa9a711e81&quot;&gt;fines&lt;/a&gt; placed on reckless driving, for instance a failure to yield to a pedestrian would cost a driver $200 instead of $50.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet almost five years after it was announced Vision-Zero has not stopped the demands for better protection for bikers in the district. In fact, despite the goal of no zero injuries or deaths by 2024, traffic collisions involving bikes have increased over the past 10 years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Number of DC Bicycle Collisions&quot; aria-label=&quot;Interactive line chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-cNGxq&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/cNGxq/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2018, the numbers of bikers injured on the streets of Washington peaked at 630 riders, according to data from the District Department of Transportation (DDOT). It appears not even the change in fines brought on by the Vision-Zero Initiative was enough to decrease the number of biker accidents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those involved in the districts biking community, like Browne, these numbers are not a surprise.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We see vision zero as not really being a bike thing and more as a directive to encourage safer driving in the city,” Browne said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Terry Owens, the Public Information Officer for DDOT, is adamant that the Vision-Zero Initiative should continue and will protect bikers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Owens says that the Mayor’s announcement in 2015 and the increase to traffic fines were just the initial steps of the policy. In 2018 further plans attached to the initiative, include installing new left turn infrastructure on intersections to prevent cars cutting across lanes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While Browne sees the plan right now doing little to changing the actual infrastructure of the city, he does note that if it were changed to be more accommodating to bikers than fatalities and injuries would begin to lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Transforming infrastructure has been suggested, by &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.smithsonianmag.com/smart-news/fort-collins-santa-monica-and-dc-are-among-top-10-bicycle-friendly-cities-new-report-180969018/&quot;&gt;other cities&lt;/a&gt;, as a way to curb pedestrian and biker collisions with cars. Prioritizing which Wards to alter first may be key to bringing down the numbers as three Wards in the district, currently account for over 70-percent of all collisions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;DC and Seattle Bike Collisions Per 10,000 Residents&quot; aria-label=&quot;Interactive line chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-q7hIN&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/q7hIN/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was in Ward Six, the third highest bicycle collision rate in the city, where Habib was struck by the charter bus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, since these policies are now just being implemented the city will not know for a few years if they will work. However, looking at Seattle, which adopted traffic infrastructure projects to accommodate their bikers earlier than the district, could provide the answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.seattletimes.com/seattle-news/transportation/the-best-bike-city-in-america-thats-seattle-apparently/&quot;&gt;Bicycling Magazine&lt;/a&gt; voted Seattle in 2018 as the best bike city in America. The magazine cited the city’s construction of concrete barriers between roads and bike lanes as well as rail sections for bikers to lean on while they were stopped as innovative ways to protect bikers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Total Number of Bicycle Collisions in DC and Seattle&quot; aria-label=&quot;Interactive line chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-Trvk1&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/Trvk1/2/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Looking at the data for bicycle collisions, provided by both cities’ department of transportation, shows that infrastructure created in Seattle over the past 5 years has made a difference.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 2018 8 per 10,000 district residents were involved in a bicycle collision versus only 6 residents in Seattle. This is even more striking given Seattle has about 30,000 more citizens than the district.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet despite Seattle’s ambitious infrastructure projects, even they have not reached zero fatalities with two bikers killed in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the Vision-Zero Initiative begins to be implemented, officials may want to scale back the zero fatality and injury number by 2024. However, looking at Seattle, were similar efforts to change the infrastructure done in the district then it may finally begin to reverse the trend of bicycle crashes.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 02:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/dc-cycling-accidents/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/dc-cycling-accidents/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Rising Homicide Rates Devastates Trans+ Community</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Hate crimes have been on the rise for members within the trans+ community in recent years, having doubled in the short span of just three years.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The LGBTQ+ community has been caught in the crossfires of hatred &amp;amp; political discourse in recent years, which has led to increased demand for visibility for its people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was the case for Ashanti Carmon, who was murdered in a shooting the day before Transgender Day of Visibility. Murdered in Prince George’s County, Md., the community was devastated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carmon was a beacon of light for the people closest to her. This truly devastated the close-knit community of trans+ individuals in D.C. and Maryland, according to Earline Budd, case manager at HIPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.hips.org/&quot;&gt;HIPS&lt;/a&gt; is a non-profit organization that aims to “enhance community, health, and individual wellness” for individuals and communities impacted by sexual exchange and/or drug use.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budd has been an advocate for the LGBTQ+ community for the past 20 years, having served as the first transgender women at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://ohr.dc.gov/&quot;&gt;Office of Human Rights&lt;/a&gt;. Before this, she was a founding member and Executive Director of D.C.’s only agency working exclusively with transgenders: &lt;a href=&quot;https://lgbtq.dc.gov/page/transgender-health-empowerment-inc&quot;&gt;Transgender Health Empowerment, Inc.&lt;/a&gt;, (T.H.E.).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trans+ individuals face issues unique to other members within the LGBTQ+ community, who are often facing higher rates of stigma, according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://assets2.hrc.org/files/assets/resources/AntiTransViolence-2018Report-Final.pdf?_ga=2.135557365.511305744.1554410510-1928837955.1549054148&quot;&gt;Human Rights Campaign&lt;/a&gt; (HRC).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We try to stick with each other because only my closest friends truly understand the daily struggles I face,” says Alex Yanuzzi, a transgender student at American University. “For example, not having easy access to gender-neutral bathrooms in my dorm is a real struggle.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Social structures, familial hardships, lack of representation, and harmful political agendas are some of the main causes of anti-trans stigma, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://assets2.hrc.org/files/assets/resources/AntiTransViolence-2018Report-Final.pdf?_ga=2.135557365.511305744.1554410510-1928837955.1549054148&quot;&gt;HRC&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Comparison of Bias-Motivated LGBTQ+ Homicides&amp;amp;nbsp; &amp;amp;nbsp;&amp;amp;nbsp;&quot; aria-label=&quot;Interactive line chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-rycxi&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/rycxi/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Rising rates of bias-motivated homicides within the LGBTQ community are a true concern. It is very disproportionate for the trans+ community, where in 2014 there was only 69 homicides. In 2017, this number skyrocketed to 119 homicides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly a 60% increase, it is very clear that more attention must be drawn to the trans+ community who are disproportionately being murdered in comparison to other groups within the LGBTQ+ community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Bias Motivated LGBTQ+ Homicides&quot; aria-label=&quot;Grouped Column Chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-6DZfy&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/6DZfy/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;548&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anti-lesbian homicides have actually gone down compared to the sharp contrast of rising homicides amongst the trans+ community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Part of the issue, as explained by Jordan Dashow of HRC, is that many trans+ individuals often are misgendered by police and media. In addition, the FBI does not require for agencies to report hate crimes, which Dashow predicts FBI’s numbers on trans+ homicides are only a “fraction of such violence.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After transgender Matthew Shepard was killed in 2009, The Matthew Shepard and James Byrd, JR., Hate Crimes Prevention Act was enacted to try and curb the high rates of murders in the trans+ community.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Trump administration have been &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/health/2019/04/24/trump-administration-prepares-rule-that-civil-rights-groups-worry-may-deny-care-transgender-patients/?noredirect=on&amp;amp;utm_term=.74e1c274de0b&quot;&gt;attempting&lt;/a&gt; to provide health care providers the option on whether or not they choose to treat trans individuals. This provides faith-based health organizations more autonomy with transgender individuals, according to a recent article published by Ariana Cha, Washington Post journalist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Health care within the trans community is not focused on nearly enough by the administration. They are human beings too who deserve the same proper treatment as everyone else, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vox.com/policy-and-politics/2019/4/22/18510894/supreme-court-gay-transgender-lgbtq-rights&quot;&gt;German Lopez&lt;/a&gt;, writer for Vox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nearly a decade after the Shepard Act, hate-crimes across the board are only increasing. This can be observed by taking one look at FBI’s statistics on hate crimes online. Of these statistics, stood out the high reporting of gay homicides.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While they may occur more frequently, it is important to keep in mind again that many transgender homicides often go unreported as part of the community for a multitude of reasons, ranging from family to misgendering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Equal Employment Opportunity Commission (EEOC) is one of many examples of laws that attempt to help solve the issue at hand, but are not direct enough in their language which allows for too many loopholes of discriminatory cases that go unheard within the trans community, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://searchlf.ama-assn.org/undefined/documentDownload?uri=%2Funstructured%2Fbinary%2Fletter%2FLETTERS%2F2018-3-27-Letter-to-Azar-re-Response-to-Proposed-Rule.pdf&quot;&gt;a letter&lt;/a&gt; sent on behalf of the American Medical Association sharing their concerns with the administration supporting harmful anti-trans rhetoric. 
One other example of the loopholes is the &lt;a href=&quot;https://transgenderlawcenter.org/resources/id/ca-sb179&quot;&gt;Gender Recognition Act&lt;/a&gt; (GRA) in the United Kingdom, which only allows for a gender transition only after having to medically prove they have gender dysmorphia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, anti-trans policies disproportionately affect trans women of color, according to analyzation of data I did from publicly available data through the &lt;a href=&quot;http://avp.org/wp-content/uploads/2018/01/a-crisis-of-hate-january-release.pdf&quot;&gt;National Coalition of Anti-Violence Programs&lt;/a&gt; (NCAVP). Of the 52 LGBTQ+ homicide victims profiled, half were transwomen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Of these transwomen, 20 were black and three were LatinX. This statistic can be viewed below in a map that demonstrates just how vast of an issue these rising homicide rates are.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More attention must be brought to these transwomen of color. The lack of current political commentary is felt in waves amongst these communities. This dehumanizing process should not exist. Of those women killed, almost all were shot in passing just going to the grocery store or driving home for work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only were they innocently killed, but they were continued to be disgraced by media and police, who misgendered nearly half of these 26 trans people, according to the data from NCAVP. How many more people must die for the administration to wake up and do something about it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Misgendered Trans+ Victims&quot; aria-label=&quot;Locator Maps&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-LlPKK&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/LlPKK/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;524&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Data covered by NCAVP is only snapshot of the vast homicides across the country amongst the trans+ community, which can often lead to the misgendering observed by this map.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Budd, along with everyone touched by Carmon, had a vigil this past weekend to honor her memory.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 05 May 2019 01:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/rising-trans-homimicide-rate/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/rising-trans-homimicide-rate/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Voting Culture in Texas After the Supreme Court’s Decision in Shelby County v Holder (2013)</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The Voting Rights Act prohibits anyone from being denied his or her right to vote on the basis of the color of their skin or their race. The act specifically outlined policy changes to try to ensure that minority people would not be denied their right to vote anymore. Shelby County v. Holder (2013) was a historic Supreme Court case ruled that the preclearance provision of the Voting Rights Act was unconstitutional. Since Section 5 depended on Section 4, it has a lack of power unless Congress were to introduce a new formula for calculating which areas needed federal examiners. This decision meant that states had complete freedom in implementing new voting laws, and did not have to wait to receive clearance to act upon the laws. Within hours of the Court’s decision, voting laws across the country were changing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Texas was one of the many states that got assigned federal examiners to watch over elections after the Voting Rights Act was passed. This implementation of federal examiners were calculated through different formulas, such as seeing is less than 50% of the voting age population voted in the 1965 election. Without sections 4 and 5 of the act, Texas was now free to implement election laws without having to seek clearance from the government. In 2012, the U.S District Court of Columbia struck down a Texas voter identification law, saying that the state could not provide sufficient evidence that the law would not discriminate against black and Latino voters (Brennan Center for Justice). After the Shelby County v. Holder decision, Texas legislature drafted a new law that required voter identification.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the Census data, I compiled the demographics of the population in Texas in 2010. The last Census was taken in 2010, so that is why the concrete data is only available for that year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Texas Population Demographics: 2010&quot; aria-label=&quot;Column Chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-CeSvH&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/CeSvH/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;500&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I looked at all of the demographics for the voting population in each election year. The following charts show the compiled data of the demographics of the population, citizens, registered voters, and people that actually voted for each year. First, I looked at the two midterms surrounding the court decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Texas 2010 Election Demographics&quot; aria-label=&quot;Column Chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-5Mb7b&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/5Mb7b/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;385&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;2014 Texas Election Demographics&quot; aria-label=&quot;Column Chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-Cbo2b&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/Cbo2b/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;423&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since presidential elections have different turnouts than midterms do, I wanted to look at the two presidential elections surrounding the court’s decision.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Voter information in Texas 2012&quot; aria-label=&quot;Column Chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-IG7Wy&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/IG7Wy/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;516&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Information for 2016 Election in Texas&quot; aria-label=&quot;Column Chart&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-b7dtn&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/b7dtn/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;487&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the data provided by the Census, the voting demographics between each of the groups accounted for did not have a huge difference. In general, they both had low turnout. White people had the highest turnout, and all minority groups had low turnout. I cannot accurately say that the court decision affected this election cycle based on the data provided.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;INTERVIEWS&lt;/strong&gt;
I had email correspondence with Cecilia Aguilera, who is a fellow with the Voting Rights Institute under the Campaign Legal Center. I asked her the following two questions: 
How have the voting laws in Texas changed since Shelby County v. Holder (2013)?
How has the culture at polling places affected the minority vote?
Her response:
“…many states, including Texas, have increased restrictive voting laws and practices since the Supreme Court struck down the preclearance formula in the Voting Rights Act (VRA) and, by extension, the Act’s preclearance requirement, which previously applied to Texas. Among many tactics, Texas has:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.texastribune.org/2016/11/04/report-texas-holds-highest-number-polling-place-cl/&quot;&gt;Closed hundreds of precincts&lt;/a&gt;, some of them in neighborhoods with &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.thenation.com/article/there-are-868-fewer-places-to-vote-in-2016-because-the-supreme-court-gutted-the-voting-rights-act/&quot;&gt;large minority and/or Democratic populations&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Instituted one of the strictest voter ID laws in the nation, which CLC challenged in &lt;a href=&quot;https://campaignlegal.org/cases-actions/veasey-v-abbott&quot;&gt;Veasey v. Abbott&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stepped up voter purges&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Engaged in alleged voter intimidation, including the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/06/13/us/texas-woman-voter-fraud.html&quot;&gt;conviction&lt;/a&gt; of a woman who was erroneously told by a poll worker that she could vote while on parole and subsequently sentenced to five years in prison, and false claims by election officials that nearly 100,000 non-citizens had voted in the 2018 elections. In reality, the majority of those voters were naturalized citizens who could legally cast a ballot; CLC recently won a &lt;a href=&quot;https://campaignlegal.org/press-releases/clc-and-partners-settle-texas-end-targeting-naturalized-citizen-voters&quot;&gt;settlement&lt;/a&gt; against the state. The documentary Rigged: The Voter Suppression Playbook features the story of a Texas sheriff who has been accused of intimidating Latino residents from voting by arresting and detaining individuals who allegedly voted illegally.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Brennan Center has additional information about voter restrictions enacted since 2013 on its &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brennancenter.org/new-voting-restrictions-america&quot;&gt;website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To your second question, I am not personally familiar with the culture that has developed at Texas polling places. However, generally speaking, precinct closures can lead to longer lines - a problem that was &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chron.com/news/politics/election/article/Long-lines-and-machines-down-at-multiple-polling-13366520.php&quot;&gt;reported&lt;/a&gt; in Texas during the 2018 midterms. In turn, although Texas law requires employers to grant employees “sufficient” time off to vote, voters caring for children or other loved ones may not be able to commit the time needed to stand in line. As one of the articles I provided above addresses, closures may also require voters to travel further to cast a ballot, which can have adverse effects on individuals with limited transportation options. Unlike some states, Texas requires an excuse to cast an absentee ballot.
Regarding voter ID, the district court in the Veasey case &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.chron.com/news/politics/election/article/Long-lines-and-machines-down-at-multiple-polling-13366520.php&quot;&gt;found&lt;/a&gt; that Texas’s voter ID law disproportionately impacted minority voters who, by virtue of where they tend to live in Texas, have little need for any of the acceptable forms of ID. They also experience poverty and engage in wage work at higher rates, making it difficult and expensive for them to collect the necessary documents and stand in line at a government office to obtain the required ID. (If you’re interested in learning more about how difficult it can be for residents living in poverty to obtain ID, I recommend visiting the websites for Vote Riders and Spread The Vote.) These hurdles may lead low-income-earning residents to forego registering to vote altogether. 
Voter purges are problematic for several reasons. Individuals who move frequently, whether for work or more affordable options, may not receive legally mandated notice that they need to confirm their address in order to avoid being purged. For context on how many voters may be affected by this issue, the Supreme Court observed in A. Phillip Randolph Inst. v. Husted that some 40 percent of Americans do not have the USPS forward their mail after they move. Certainly, people should update their voter registration; however, while many states allow for same day registration for new or purged voters, Texas does not. If someone does not know they have been purged because notice was sent to an old address, they cannot re-register before the registration deadline. Additionally, there have been major issues and alleged due process violations with how some states have carried out purges.
Finally, threatening prosecution for voting violations - even ones committed as a result of government errors and good-faith misunderstandings of the law - can scare eligible voters from the polls. Returning citizens especially may not know that they are eligible to vote and may be especially reticent to register or cast a ballot in light of recent “voter fraud” prosecutions in Texas and North Carolina. When Texas officials announced that 98,000 people may have voted illegally, local election officials subsequently sent letters to lawfully registered naturalized citizens informing them that they had to produce documentation to prove they were citizens, or face being purged; many may have avoided providing this documentation out of fear that they had been mistakenly registered and would be prosecuted.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my next interview, I had a brief phone conversation with Alexa Ura. Ura is a demographics reporter for the Texas Tribune. We discussed how recently, Texas Attorney General refused to give Congress information on the voter roll review. The Attorney General’s office treated congressional request as a public information request, which under Texas law, allows the Texas Attorney General’s Office to control what information is withheld. Though people are becoming more and more aware of voter purges, it seems that the state is managing to find loopholes to avoid disclosing information about the voter disenfranchisement that they performed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my last interview, I spoke briefly to Derek Rosenfeld, who is a specialist on voting rights and elections along with fair courts. He works for the Brennan Center for Justice as a media strategist. Rosenfeld gave me more insight on how catastrophic the decision in Shelby County v Holder was. Under the original Voting Rights Act, certain places that had a history of voter suppression had to get clearance before passing any laws regarding election. But, after the Supreme Court struck down that portion of the law, Texas, like many places, were free to make new election laws. Rosenfeld explained to me that within hours of the court decision, the Attorney General, Greg Abbott, released a statement saying that voter ID law would go immediately into effect, along with plans for redistricting. Rosenfeld explained that people had been waiting to continue to suppress the vote for minority communities, and the decision of Shelby County v Holder opened the gate for elected officials to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Voter Registration by County&lt;/strong&gt;
For the midterms of 2010 and 2014, I wanted to compare the amount of registered voters in each county. First, I calculated the demographics of each county based on data provided by the US Census Bureau and the Texas Secretary of State. To calculate whether the county population was majority white or minority majority, I looked to see if the white population was above or below fifty percent. Then, I looked at each county’s number of registered voters for 2010 and 2014 and compared the percent change. The counties with the most negative change in number of registered voters were Motley (-13.08%), Menard (-10.58%), Coke (-10.22%), Garza (-9.37%), Wichita (-8.98), Terrell (-8.97), Floyd (-8.44), Concho (-7.84%), and Stonewall (-7.33%), and Duval (-7.12%). Garza, Terrell, Floyd, Concho, and Duval are all minority majority counties.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Changes in Texas Registered Voters&quot; aria-label=&quot;USA texas counties choropleth map&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-xoB1N&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/xoB1N/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Voting purges are a common practice by election officials to keep an up-to-date list of eligible voters. In essence, it is meant to remove people from voting list that have moved to a new place or that have passed away. Unfortunately, this process is often flawed and ends up removing eligible voters from voting lists. The problem with this is that people usually do not know that their names have been removed, and by the time they find out it is election day so there is nothing to be done to allow them to vote in that election. According to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.brennancenter.org/sites/default/files/publications/Purges_Growing_Threat_2018.pdf&quot;&gt;Brennan Center for Justice&lt;/a&gt;, 360,000 more voters were removed from Texas voting rolls between 2012-2014 than between 2008 and 2010. The 2012-2014 period was right when Shelby County v. Holder was decided and Texas regained complete control over election laws. 
It is proven fact that there is more voter turnout for presidential elections compared to state and local elections. 2012 and 2016 were both huge election years. President Obama was running for reelection in 2012 against Republican Mitt Romney. In 2016, the presidential race recieved huge media coverage as Republican Donald Trump and Democrat Hillary Clinton faced off. Texas voting showed a lot of changes between the two elections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the data that I had already collected on the counties of Texas and their demographics, and I used the data found on the Texas Secretary of State website to see the amount of registered voters in November of both 2012 and 2016. I compared the amount of change that happened in the numbers. It is important that I looked at 2012 first, because 2013 is when the Supreme Court struck down parts of the Voting Rights Act. After collecting the data, I noticed large percentages of changes in voter registration. The counties with the most negative changes were Terrell (-21.70%), Frio (-11.94), Kenedy (-11.91), Foard (-11.90), Loving (-10.57), Menard (-9.16), Presidio (-7.58), Haskell (-7.12), Donley (-6.32), and Coke (-5.76). Out of these top ten counties, Foard, Loving, Menard, Haskell, Donley, and Coke have a majority white population. Terrell, Frio, Kenedy, and Presidio have minority majority population. The county with the highest amount of voter registration increase, Denton (20.18%), is a  majority white county.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe title=&quot;Changes in Texas Registered Voters&quot; aria-label=&quot;USA texas counties choropleth map&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-2czDT&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/2czDT/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through my research, I found that Texas has an extremely flawed history with voting registration. Between redistricting, voter ID laws, and vote roll purges, the state effectively suppresses the minority vote throughout different counties. Shelby County v Holder (2013) allowed Texas to perform this voter disenfranchisement. The Texas legislature and election committees need to be held accountable for the amount of voices they have suppressed throughout the recent election years.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 19:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/texas-voting-restriction-results/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/texas-voting-restriction-results/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Going to the Gym Can Lead to Improvements in Mental Health </title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;In the United States, around 1 in 5 adults experience mental health issues. In 2017, that was about 46.6 million adults. According to the National Institute of Mental Health, mental health falls on a scales and ranges from mild to severe. Two general categories of mental health are Any Mental Illness (AIM) and Serious Mental Illness (SMI).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://media.self.com/photos/5b7c4e71ecbb7f4c41c77335/4:3/w_728/triangle-pose-beginner-yoga.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;Stock yoga photo, I guess&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the National Institute of Mental Health, AIM can be defined as “a mental, behavioral, or emotional disorder. AMI can vary in impact, ranging from no impairment to mild, moderate, and even severe impairment.” The figures below show the percentage of adults who face AIM through different demographics such as sex, age, and race. The overall percentage of adults who have AIM is 18.9%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;2017 Prevalence of Any Mental Illness Among U.S. Adults by Sex&quot; aria-label=&quot;Bar Chart&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/6vAqc/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;706&quot; height=&quot;166&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;2017 Prevalence of Any Mental Illness Among U.S. Adults by Age&quot; aria-label=&quot;Bar Chart&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/vi3cJ/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;714&quot; height=&quot;190&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In terms of age, the group that experiences mental health range from the ages 18-25 years old. These years are known to be when you grow the most in your life. Adults go through various phases during this time like entering college or the workforce. These stressful times can cause various adults to show symptoms of various mental health illnesses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;2017 Prevalence of Any Mental Illness Among U.S. Adults by Race&quot; aria-label=&quot;Bar Chart&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/wyg4s/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;707&quot; height=&quot;286&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the National Alliance on Mental Illness (NAMI), 60% of adults with mental health did not receive mental health services last year. Lizzie Fernandez, a junior studying Health Promotions at American University and member of the Health Promotion and Advocacy Center (HPAC) adds that many people are apprehensive when it comes to talking about mental health and how to go about it. “During my office hours, students dealing with mental health come in and are nervous to discuss it. Since it is a touchy subject, awareness to how many people experience mental health needs to be increased. As well as ways in which to positively deal with your mental health.” According to Alayna Berkowitz, a psychologist and staff clinician at American University’s Counseling Center, many people facing mental health are constantly looking for ways to improve. “Many think that these ways are very costly and require therapy or counseling. However, there are some ways you can improve your mental health right now.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sam Moran, a junior student at American University, experiences anxiety. He explains it can be hard to find time to focus on your mental health, especially during peak school times. “I don’t really have time to try and improve my mental health. I know I should put it first, but I don’t know how well it would work compared to the current treatment I’m on now. In a study conducted with 50 participants at American University, 29 adults said they have mental health. Of those 29, 22 adults said they are willing to improve their mental health. The question is: how?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One common way that not many people realize is exercise. While many know that exercise can help with a lot of physical and health aspects such as obesity, diabetes, cancer, cardiovascular health, etc., many don’t realize that exercise releases a hormone that lead to improvements in mood. Improvements in mood can lead to overall better mental health. Fernandez states, “Going to the gym can help with mental health by boosting endorphins, the body’s natural neuropeptide that boosts mood and dulls pain.” Exercise increases the volume of specific brain regions. This leads to better blood supply that improves the delivery of oxygen and nutrients and an increase in neurohormones. An increase of blood circulation to the brain leads to an influence on the psychological reactivity to stress. Exercise creates various beneficial effects on mental health like distraction, self-efficiency, and social interaction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The figure below shows the percent of US adults who have specific mental illnesses like depression, anxiety, bipolar disorder, schizophrenia, and posttraumatic stress disorder (PTSD). Since there are many different types of mental illnesses, different exercise affects them in different ways. Mental health illnesses are distinguished by a cognitive flexibility that creates bad habits such as repeating unhelpful behaviors, restricting the ability to process new information, and reducing the capacity to find new solutions to constant problems. Exercise increases the potential for cognitive flexibility by reducing the amount of stress by releasing endorphins. While the most common mental illness in US adults is anxiety, the correlation between exercise and anxiety is the lowest. Exercise affects anxiety by limiting the intensity of anxiety symptoms as well as how often they occur, temporarily. While exercise does affect anxiety, it positively affects depression the more. Exercise affects depression by changing the perspective you have on your self-image and self-esteem, releasing mood-boosting endorphins, and producing certain proteins.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;% of Adults who Have Mental Illnesses in US&amp;amp;nbsp;&quot; aria-label=&quot;Column Chart&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/npLNj/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; width=&quot;622&quot; height=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to NAMI, “Individuals living with serious mental illness face an increased risk of having chronic medical conditions. Adults in the U.S. living with serious mental illness die on average 25 years earlier than others, largely due to treatable medical conditions.” Awareness of the importance of treatment for adults experiencing mental illnesses needs to be increased. Especially when some treatments can be done independently, like exercise. Physical activity leads to various beneficial effects on different mental health illnesses like releasing endorphins (the body’s natural painkiller), reducing stress, allowing more cognitive flexibility, improving mood, and boosting the ability to sleep. All these effects, positively affect various mental illnesses like anxiety, depression, mood disorders, PTSD, etc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Serena Thapa, a student at American University and employee of the AU Fitness Centers believes the gym fosters a space of interaction and motivation for personal goals, whether they be physical or mental related. “Everyone that walks into the facility has an intention. They either come in wanting to work on their fitness, blow off some steam, or simply just see friendly faces while they go on a light jog or walk on the treadmill. All and all, the gym allows individuals to be at ease and thus improve their mental health.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 15:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/gym-and-mental-health/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/gym-and-mental-health/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>So Trump Won the Midwest in 2016. What are his chances in 2020?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For years, the Democratic “Blue Wall” of the rust belt seemed impenetrable, but after Donald Trump’s shocking victory in the 2016 Presidential Election many were left wondering how this ruptured. How did Trump flip these states and resonate with that region in ways his Republican counterparts largely could not?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s break it down. This “Blue Wall” is best defined as the Midwestern U.S. States and the District of Columbia that the Democratic Party traditionally won in Presidential elections from the years 1992 and 2012. Previously, this gave the Democratic party an advantage in the electoral college.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2016, however, Donald Trump dismantled this with promises of economic stability and job opportunity, among other strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the time came for the election three years ago, voters in the Midwest were losing labor jobs at a rapid speed. And more than that, this downward slope is chronic and stagnant. Not much has been done in the past to revive this once boisterous and booming area as they have mainly been suffering from the lack of recent economic policy implementation that would benefit them directly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Basically, the rust belt has been given this name for a reason. It used to be the largest industrial center in the United States. In the 30 years since the beginning of its decline, though, all of those manufacturing outposts that originated here and brought much success to the area have left. Now, the interior of our country is deteriorating, both literally through the rotting of industrial infrastructure and figuratively as the economy present continues to decay.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During their campaigns for presidency, both Donald Trump and Bernie Sanders appealed heavily to this specific group of westerners living and residing in the Midwest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A senior studying political science at American University in Washington D.C., AJ Pentaleri, explained this phenomena. He said, “Sanders used his platform to blame the business owners who have no remorse for their employees. They generally only care about profit and capitalizing the amount of money that they can produce.” So, when they decide to move a company out of the U.S., all of these people are out of their job.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Sanders didn’t get the nomination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In large part, this is how Trump took the majority of electoral college votes. Pentaleri added that compared to Hillary Clinton, who basically said that jobs like coal mining were no longer necessary in America and didn’t focus enough energy on Wisconsin, Michigan, Ohio, and Pennsylvania, Donald Trump’s message was appealing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/rust1.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Specifically, Trump paved his way to the White House in 2016 strategically by focusing on these people who were otherwise considered deplorable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“He offered them a scapegoat for their continued suffering that was neither the government nor their wealth ridden bosses.” said Pentaleri. Instead, Trump acknowledged that someone out there was taking their jobs away from them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this scenario, Pentaleri said, it is the immigrants who work more hours a day for less money, and those in the developing country that big businesses moved to on their own autonomy because manufacturing there is cheaper and has fewer regulations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By 2018, after two years of Trump being office, we are presented with yet another shift in the rust belt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/rust2.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Change between Trump 2016 percentage and 2019 approval&quot; aria-label=&quot;USA states choropleth map&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-k3NEh&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/k3NEh/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to the Federal Election Commission and Morning Consult, voters in the rust belt largely thought the economy improved since 2016, but either did not attribute it to Trump or it didn’t matter.
Trump promised to bring back tons of jobs to this area for manufacturing, but this never actually happened and still, he didn’t do much of anything to actually help them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/rust3.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In 2018 the election was less national…and state representatives generally know more about state issues than their national counterparts.” said Andrew Ballard, a Political Science professor at American University. He is an expert on American politics and is particularly interested in voting behavior.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ballard continued, “their [state representative] campaigns are more direct and policy initiatives are geared towards the actual people that are affected by such change.” He also explained that it soon became readily apparent as the primaries progressed that Democratic candidates knew more about issues surrounding the rust belt and organized labor than the Republicans they were running against.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe title=&quot;Percent GDP Growth in 2018&quot; aria-label=&quot;USA states choropleth map&quot; id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-yCISb&quot; src=&quot;//datawrapper.dwcdn.net/yCISb/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;430&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;!function(){&quot;use strict&quot;;window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(void 0!==a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var e in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;]){var t=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-&quot;+e)||document.querySelector(&quot;iframe[src*='&quot;+e+&quot;']&quot;);t&amp;&amp;(t.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][e]+&quot;px&quot;)}})}();&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is not shocking to see from these graphs that Midwestern GDP growth has lagged behind much of the country, even during the middle of Trump’s presidency in 2018.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a new presidential election approaching in 2020, there is another opportunity for the Midwest to go against the tide. This time, they can decide to either remain red and basically guarantee Trump’s second term, or voters can bring the region back to blue.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The latter looks more promising.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Green New Deal is an initiative proposed by Democrats and led by representative Alexandria Ocasio-Cortez that aims to transform the greying economy into a sustainable one that is, according to the definition on the Green Party’s official website, “environmentally sound, economically viable, and socially responsible.” Its goal is basically to address climate issues with implementing cleaner energy while also increasing wages, fairness, and economic opportunity. This policy change leans toward a democratic shift once again in the Midwest and brings forth a more advantageous and economically sound future. 
Along the same token, Bernie Sanders has decided yet again to run for the presidency. According to recent polls concerning his Town Halls, much support for his movement lies in the Midwest. He hopes to take back this area with his platform of policies like Medicare For All, taxing the rich, and offering free college tuition to all Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These ambitions economic policies brought forward by Democrats, in addition to the slower than expected economic growth in the Midwest, lends itself to the real possibility of a party turnover in 2020 that is in favor of a renewal of the Midwestern “Blue Wall” and the overall success of the Democratic ticket, resulting in Presidency.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 15:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/voting-trends-again/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/voting-trends-again/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Cruise Ships: Planet Destroyers in Disguise</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Cruise ship tourism is at an all-time-high, with an expected increase of 67% of overall cruise line passengers from 2009 to 2019. Most ships can carry up to 5,000 passengers  for days at a time, providing them with everything they could possibly need. With swimming pools, restaurants, shops, gyms, saunas, casinos, laundry rooms and thousands of living quarters, these vessels are practically floating cities that come with hidden environmental costs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/cruise1.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The amount of fuel from one ship could fill 12,000 cars, according to Oceana . This means the 24-hour energy needed to sustain such a large vessel causes a non-stop transmission of harmful pollutants into the air, which can contain sulfur dioxide and nitrogen oxides, which are principal components of acid rain. The fuel causing these transmissions is 50 times more harmful than regular fuel when burned .. If inhaled in excess it could even lead to brain tumors and diseases like Alzheimer’s . Many cruise passengers are unaware they are breathing in toxic particles equivalent to those in busy cities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But air pollution is not the only problem, and humans are not the only ones affected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;More than 1,000 tons of waste are generated each day on these vessels. The ships’ wastes range from sewage from toilets, sinks, showers, kitchens, laundry machines; paired with oily fluids, lubricants, grease, cleaning fluids, garbage and solid wastes . Ships can legally dump all of these into the ocean as long as it’s done more than four miles away from a coast.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The amount of sewage that gets dumped is staggering. It’s really, really crazy because of the concentration of the people on those ships. Even if the sewage is being dumped a few miles off shore, that is still definitely going to come into the coast and affect marine life. It’s not that far,” said Dr. Jesse Meiller, marine ecologist and environmental toxicologist.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a combination of air and waste pollution from cruise ships, marine life is impacted in several ways. According to Dr. Meiller, particles from the fuel exhaust settle on the water surface and can either float or end up in the bottom sediments. Some of the finer ones can dissolve in the water and be taken in by any fish or filter feeders. The problem is that many of the components of fossil fuels are persistent organic pollutants, meaning they don’t break down easily. Then they start to bio accumulate, where organisms take in a chemical and build it up in their systems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Not all chemicals bio accumulate, but many of those from fossil fuels, like the ones from cruise ships, do. Orcas are going to eat a whole bunch of seals, and if those seals have eaten fish which have also eaten a lot of krill, by the time they build up to the orcas, they have high levels of pollutants in their systems,” said Dr. Meiller.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In contrast to air particles, wastes that are dumped into the ocean can have much heavier and quicker impacts on shallow water ecosystems. When sewage is thrown overboard a lot of nutrients go into the water, which can cause algae to grow. This is harmful because algae do not live long and usually grow on the surface of the water. If they grow in really dense communities they can block the sunlight to the bottom, keeping other plants from growing down low and making it hard for organisms to live under water without oxygen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on the amount of annual voyages made by some of the top seven cruise lines, the Caribbean is the most visited region in the world. With almost 700 voyages offered in 2019 to 2020, it is being visited by over 400 vessels that carry a total of more than 1.2 million passengers (only including these 7 cruise lines). This may suggest that this oceanic area is most exposed to pollution generated by cruise ships.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/cruise2.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If waste is dumped in the middle of the ocean, it’s not going to be as much of an issue for marine ecosystems. But illegal dumping does happen too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There have been ships in the past that have been fined for dumping water contaminated with suds and that could be really really bad. Cruise lines, like Carnival, have been fined for dumping everything from used mattresses to other garbage in the ocean,” said Dr. Kiho Kim, marine ecologist and Executive Director for the Center for Teaching, Research and Learning (CTRL) at American University.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Based on Carnival Cruise Line’s voyages in 2019 leading into 2020, about 60,000 passengers sail with them to the Caribbean, followed by about 25,000 to the Bahamas. These areas face large amounts of tourism and are more prone to the affects of waste pollution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/cruise3.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After Carnival Cruise Line got in trouble for violating ocean regulations in 2013, they began a five-year Environmental Compliance Plan (ECP), requiring third-party audits and court-appointed oversight . On their website they even say, “The health and vitality of the oceans, seas, and communities through which we travel is absolutely essential to our business. That makes protecting the environment and biodiversity one of our most critical areas of focus.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although Dr.Kim said he doesn’t think illegal waste dumping is a frequent threat to the oceans, he said one of the biggest ways he thinks ships affect marine life is through sound.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These ships make a lot of noise. You may not hear it because you are insulted in a cabin above the engine. But if you are a marine creature that depends on sound for communication, navigation or getting a sense of the environment, the noise can be literally deafening,” said Dr. Kim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So why are people not paying attention? To me, it seemed like these impacts were clear indicators of contaminated oceans, physical destruction of natural environments and a lack of adequate legislation to protect the ocean.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The reason why we don’t worry so much about ecosystems along the coast of the United States, for example, is because they have already been damaged. Even in the Caribbean coral reefs have declined significantly over the last 50 to 60 years. That’s in part because of climate change, but largely because of human exploitation, like the dumping of sewage. They are seeing big impacts of human encroachment,” said Dr. Kim.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Another point to consider is the complication of dealing with rules in international waters. Most of the ocean is not governed by any one country. While we have treaties and agreements that all entities are supposed to abide by, no one is actually policing or overseeing those waters, and no one is really funding it anyway. Dr. Meiller described it as a “no man’s land.” “It’s such a complicated issue that people don’t want to tackle it. They want to tackle something that is more concrete and discreet that they can actually handle,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 04 May 2019 14:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/cruise-pollution/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://comm-260.github.io/spring-2019/spring-2019/cruise-pollution/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
