<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COMM-260 Quant Methods &amp; Data Viz (Spring 2018)</title>
    <description>Final projects from students in Quantitative Methods &amp; Data Visualization at American University Spring 2018.  
</description>
    <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 18:34:47 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 18:34:47 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Remembering the Confederacy is not just for the states that were part of it</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At the Jefferson Davis Historic Site in Fairview, Kentucky, stands a monument and a museum honoring the birthplace of the first – and only – president of the Confederate States of America. Photo courtesy of Roadside America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.roadsideamerica.com/attract/images/ky/KYFAIdavis_ks02_art1_620x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the southwest corner of Kentucky, there is a Washington Monument look-alike. At 351 feet, the obelisk is the tallest structure in Fairview. When it was constructed in 1924, it was the tallest structure in Kentucky. The obelisk, which sits on a base of solid Kentucky limestone, commemorates one of the state’s most famous sons: Jefferson Davis, president of the former Confederate States of America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Hodgenville, a town in the heart of Kentucky, the “First Lincoln Memorial” sits honoring the birthplace of Abraham Lincoln, the 16th president of the United States of America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 51 confederate sites, Kentucky, perhaps better than any other state, represents the parallel histories of the United States. In 2017, border states removed three times as many confederate monuments than former union states and states that were territories during the Civil War combined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Civil War, which split the country into North, South, and in-between from 1861 to 1865, Kentucky was one of five border states caught in the middle of the conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even today, people still feel the tension between northern and southern ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a gross oversimplification to say that everyone in the South remembers the people-owning days of the Confederacy fondly as much as it is an oversimplification to say that the northern states were unbigoted, moral beacons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a fair assessment, however, to say that the War Between the States was fought over the issue of slavery. The North wanted to abolish it. The South wanted to preserve it. That is the Confederacy’s legacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some say the men who fought for the Confederacy were heroes. Others call them racists and traitors. At what point does remembrance become reverence? In recent years, that point is being debated with greater ferocity after the Confederacy has been used to justify acts of violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, self-proclaimed white supremacist Dylann Roof killed nine African-Americans in church in Charleston, South Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017, the “Unite the Right” rally in Charlottesville, Virginia resulted in the death a counter-protester and the injuries of several others when a member of the so-called alt-right drove his car into a crowd. The impetus of the “Unite the Right” rally was to protest the removal of a statue of Confederate Gen. Robert E. Lee from a park named for the same general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Southern Poverty Law Center released in 2016 a list of all “public symbols of the Confederacy” found in the U.S. The symbols included monuments, towns, streets and schools but excluded historical sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For the final tally, the researchers excluded nearly 2,600 markers, battlefields, museums, cemeteries and other places or symbols that are largely historical in nature,” the SPLC said in their study of public Confederate symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a total of 135 symbols in the 19 states that were not members of the Confederacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;confederate-symbols&quot;&gt;Confederate symbols&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flourish-embed&quot; data-src=&quot;story/6616&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, this number is dwarfed in comparison to the number of public monuments to the former Confederate States of America that are densely scattered throughout the South. As of 2016, there were 1,354 symbols of the Confederacy in states that made up the Confederacy. Virginia, a former Confederate state, tops the list with 223 public Confederate symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is to be expected, especially given the majority of Civil War battles occurred in Southern states, particularly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.civilwar.org/learn/articles/civil-war-facts&quot;&gt;Virginia and Tennessee&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if these northern states, border states, and not-yet states fought against the Confederates on the Confederates’ own turf, why are Confederate monuments not confined to the battlegrounds and cities of the South?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That would only make sense on the grounds of remembering the nation’s history. After all you would not travel to Florida to remember the Alamo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these states have responded to the call to remove Confederate imagery from their cities. After the Charleston shooting, Kansas removed the Confederate battle flag from Wichita’s Veterans Park. In 2017, Baltimore removed all four of its Confederate statues overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the removals, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.baltimoresun.com/news/maryland/baltimore-city/bs-md-ci-monuments-removed-20170816-story.html&quot;&gt;Baltimore Mayor Catherine Pugh&lt;/a&gt; said, “They needed to come down. My concern is for the safety and security of our people.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pugh feared Charlottesville-style violence. A group of protesters had threatened to tear down the statues of Lee and Gen. Thomas “Stonewall” Jackson themselves if action was not taken by the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of Confederate symbols were established by state and local governments. Two cities in California – Fort Bragg and Confederate Corners – are named for Confederate veterans despite California being Union state that never saw a Civil War battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1868 to the middle of the 1930s, Confederate monuments and memorials were going up on an almost yearly basis in Non-confederate states, the vast majority in Kentucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half of the monuments standing in Non-confederate states today were erected before 1920.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the fifty year period between 1868 and 1918, the United Daughters of the Confederacy and the Sons of Confederate Veterans were responsible for one-fourth of monuments and symbols in non-Confederate states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early 20th century in the U.S. saw two things: the 50th anniversary of the Civil War and the rise of Jim Crow, a brutal age of racial terror. In their analysis of Confederate symbols, the SPLC saw a correlation between the increases in construction of Confederate monuments and period of Jim Crow that terrorized African-Americans in an effort to maintain white supremacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United Daughters of the Confederacy worked to erect a number of monuments to the Confederacy, but have since attempted to distance themselves from the violent white supremacists who use the same monuments to justify racism as history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The president general of the United Daughters of the Confederacy wrote in a press release shortly after the rally in Charlottesville, “We are grieved that certain hate groups have taken the Confederate flag and other symbols as their own. Our members are the ones who, like our statues, have stayed quietly in the background, never engaging in public controversy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teresa Roane, the archivist and librarian for the United Daughters of the Confederacy, said though she could not speak for her organization, it was important to know, “I’m a UDC member and I’m black.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each person gets to make his or her own decision about how to remember history. Like Roane insisted, Confederate monuments can be war memorials, too. The best way to remember history is to remember it truthfully without heroes and without excuses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 11:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/confederate_statues/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/confederate_statues/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Top 50 RPI NCAA Division I Women's Basketball Players</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Girls scattered in gyms across the country are playing basketball dreaming about becoming a Division I athlete. That dream came true for the 14 women on The American University basketball team.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://www.google.com/maps/d/embed?mid=1FlFwcD2f6DgI7v1zSp6ijlcKINZtVdYg&quot; width=&quot;640&quot; height=&quot;480&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For some girls the recruiting process begins as young as 12 or 13-years-old. For others the process picks up around 16 or 17-years-old. For those who aren’t firmiliar with the recruitng process of WBB basketball very simplified version goes like this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before your junior year of high school college coaches cannot contact you in any way other than a questionnaire. This should not scare you away from emailing or calling them. On September 1 of a recruits junior year of high school, college coaches can begin contacting them. Most recruits attending top level schools sign a National Letter of Intent on November 11 of their senior year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American University basketball star Cecily Carl began the recruitment process at the age of 15 towards the end of her freshman year of high school. 
“The recruiting process was difficult for me because I put a lot of pressure on myself and when i didn’t feel like i was doing well enough it was very tough,” said Carl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The recruiting process is different for everyone. For some it can be stressfull which makes sense considering these girls are making a decision that can impact the rest of their life before some of them can even drive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I also had a good deal of anxiety before playing major tournaments but it was a good amount of nerves,” said Carl. The major tournaments she speaks of are playe during NCAA sanctioned recruiting time periods. These weekends happen in April, July and September. The map below depicts the geopgraphy of players that are from the United States and are currently on the roster of a Top 50 RPI NCAA Division I school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-kt9ao&quot; src=&quot;https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/kt9ao/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;if(&quot;undefined&quot;==typeof window.datawrapper)window.datawrapper={};window.datawrapper[&quot;kt9ao&quot;]={},window.datawrapper[&quot;kt9ao&quot;].embedDeltas={&quot;100&quot;:517,&quot;200&quot;:450,&quot;300&quot;:425,&quot;400&quot;:425,&quot;500&quot;:400,&quot;700&quot;:400,&quot;800&quot;:400,&quot;900&quot;:400,&quot;1000&quot;:400},window.datawrapper[&quot;kt9ao&quot;].iframe=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-kt9ao&quot;),window.datawrapper[&quot;kt9ao&quot;].iframe.style.height=window.datawrapper[&quot;kt9ao&quot;].embedDeltas[Math.min(1e3,Math.max(100*Math.floor(window.datawrapper[&quot;kt9ao&quot;].iframe.offsetWidth/100),100))]+&quot;px&quot;,window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(&quot;undefined&quot;!=typeof a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var b in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])if(&quot;kt9ao&quot;==b)window.datawrapper[&quot;kt9ao&quot;].iframe.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][b]+&quot;px&quot;});&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 349 Division I women’s basketball programs in America. The ratings percentage index (RPI) which more easily translates as the ranking of teams according to their record and level of competition. The above map shows the hometown of all 656 players from the 2017-18 season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;American University head women’s basketball coach, Megan Gebbia, said there is bias when recruiting based on location.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“My feeling is that there are pockets across the United States where you will see a certain style of play and certain type of players. However there are always outliers in every area that go against what you would expect.” She continued, “I tend to recruit more in the midwest because I think they spend time on the fundamentals and may have better youth development leagues and coaches.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The larger more popular AUU tournaments are held in big cities such as Portland, Ore., Chicago, Ill., Orlando, Fla., Atlanta, Ga. and Washington, D.C. The map shows that players from those areas specifically the midwest to the east coast, make-up the majority of NCAA women’s basketball players.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Style of play can vary by region and can determine the level and type of school that recruits in a certain area. “I think that some girls that I played with who were actually from Harrisburg play faster paced basketball compared to me and other people on my team who were from small towns. Also, girls from Maryland and New Jersey seemed to play with more physicality and aggression,” said Cecily Carl who is from Mechanicsburg, Pa. which has a population of 9,000 people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Carl, the reigning Patriot League Tounrament MVP, went on to explain the difficulties of the recruiting process including that she had to travel to bigger cities for tournaments and believes the recruiting process can be improved for future athletes. “I think coaches just need to be a little more understanding that it’s very overwhelming for high school kids to deal with a bunch of people talking to them and expecting them to decide, at 16 or 17, what they are going to want their lives to be like when they’re 21 and 22.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are about 430,000 girls make up the basktball rosters of high schools across the nation. Only 17,000 of those girls will join the roster of a NCAA women’s basketball program. That means there is less than a 4 percent chance of becoming a collegiate basketball player. Of that percentage only 4 percent will play for a top 50 program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coach Gebbia had three pieces of advice on how to increase the probability of joining a top basketball program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first,”For the players that come from small towns and rural areas it is difficult to get the exposure sometimes. I would try out for the best AAU program in your state or adjoining states.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;AAU teams travel across the country to play in NCAA santioned tournaments that college coaches come to recruit at.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second, “I would also suggest going to elite camps at the schools you are interested in.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Elite camps allow for coaches and players to interact with recruits which could lead to further conversation and even the coach coming out to see you play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The third, “Finally, contact the coaching staff either yourself or through your high school/AAU coach and have them send film.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most coaches don’t make scholarship offers after only watching film. 
However, it is a great way to get on the recruiting board and can lead further recruitment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even with all of the advice in the world there are two things that can’t be taught in basketball. The first is heart. Either kids love the game or they don’t. The second is height. There is no changing genetics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/height.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The average height of a women’s basketball player is 5’11”. The tallest active player is Felicia Aiyeotan. Standing at 6 feet 9 inches Aiyeotan is from Lagos, Nigeria and is currently a junior at The University of Virginia.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The shortest active player is Jessica Laemmle. Standing at 5 feet 2 inches Laemmle is from Louisville, Kentucky and is currently a freshman at The University of Louisville.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/pie.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The five players on the court are usually made up of three guards and two forwards. Therefore it makes sense that 60 percent of current athletes are listed as guards. It also can be inferred to mean that forwards are rare, so if you’ve got some height go pick up a ball and maybe you’ll get a scholarship for it. It is also a reflection of transformation of basketball. Players like Steph Curry and Klay Thompson have revolutionized how basketball is played on all levels. Everyone one wants to be a guard because guards get to stand on the three-point-line and fire away.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Being recruited as a guard you really have to make yourself stand out. Whether you excel in ball handling, have stellar defense, shoot the 3 at a consistent high percentage, or you can do it all. You can’t just be average at something, whatever specific talent you have, you have to make sure that skill sets you apart from other who have the same skill,” said Indeya Sanders, American University freshman guard.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 17:07:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/basketball-states/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/basketball-states/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
