<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>COMM-260 Quant Methods &amp; Data Viz (Spring 2018)</title>
    <description>Final projects from students in Quantitative Methods &amp; Data Visualization at American University Spring 2018.  
</description>
    <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 22:53:00 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 22:53:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.8.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>While Louisiana School Ratings Sink, Students’ Academic Success Rises</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Elizabeth Guillen, Junior at American University states “if schools scores are low, it is highly likely that the charter school will be failing and forced to close”(Guillen, 2018). She sits across from me contemplating and sharing her experiences working with New Orleans schools. She highlights several challenges for New Orleans students- including busing, application process, and teacher hiring practices. She discusses the “inequities in schools” with passion. She is a student, who has studied and gone on an alternative break to New Orleans. Although she is a student and not a native of Louisiana, she is writing her capstone on educational equity and states the alternative break was “extremely eye opening”. But her note on accountability rings strongly- what happens to students when schools fail? What happens to students when scores change?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schools like those in Elizabeth’s story are rated according to several factors, depending on the system they use.  The scores can be composed of things such as test scores, student achievement, or other important factors. For years, Louisiana has been at the bottom of the barrel of school accountability scores compared to other states in the United States.  However, a new change in their rating system policies might show improvements on the horizon.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to put themselves on a level playing field with other states in the US, Louisiana decided to adjust its school ranking system to a more rigorous one that is used more universally.   Unlike the previous policy, which focused mainly on standardized test scores, the gains-based system places more value on student academic growth. Academic growth refers to each student and schools’ progress in a given year.  According to a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theadvocate.com/baton_rouge/news/education/article_6a15a50c-0a5e-11e7-9f98-9797fe23bfe1.html.&quot;&gt;local newspaper&lt;/a&gt;, the new system increased the percent that growth counts in a school’s rating from 7 percent to 25 percent of the overall score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theadvocate.com/baton_rouge/news/education/article_6a15a50c-0a5e-11e7-9f98-9797fe23bfe1.html&quot;&gt;same source&lt;/a&gt;. points out that the system also raises the standards by which Louisiana schools are judged from “basic” to a more advanced “mastery” level.  By upping the difficulty of their rating criteria, they have the chance to try to improve their educational quality to meet the rising standards.  Still, many citizens do not see this as a positive change in their communities. Scott Devillier, superintendent of the Zachary School District and influential member of the Superintendent’s Advisory Council, noted in an email that he was worried about a drop in scores.  Cade Brumley, president of the Superintendent’s group, has also shared his concerns with  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.theadvocate.com/baton_rouge/news/education/article_6a15a50c-0a5e-11e7-9f98-9797fe23bfe1.html&quot;&gt;local newspaper The Advocate&lt;/a&gt;. that he expected that the number of schools “with an A rating will drastically fall and the number of F rated schools will substantially increase”. The reason for this, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.lsunow.com/daily/opinion-assessment-accountability-changes-are-too-often-to-meas%20%20ure-success/article_b78c6cd0-d2d1-11e7-8f30-6b349f46909a.html&quot;&gt;former student Breanna Smith&lt;/a&gt; says, is because the changes are happening too quickly and teachers do not have the proper amount of time to adjust.  Reservations aside, the success or failure of the new program can only be assessed once the program has had time to produce results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On paper, the new system Louisiana began using in 2017 would improve their current standings.  However, data is needed to fully assess the failure or success of the new program that was implemented.  By comparing data collected that examines the percentage of “at-risk” children in a school to their Ed Navigator school accountability score, the new program can be evaluated.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The first graph shows a scatterplot of the data representing the scores for Louisiana schools under the old aggregate system.  There is a negative relationship, showing that the more economically disadvantaged children who are at a school, the worse their overall school accountability score is.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/sps2a.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The second graph shows the same thing, this time showing the school’s accountability score under the new gains-based system.  Once again there is a negative relationship, where the more economically disadvantaged kids go to a school the worse the school’s rating is. However, looking at the difference in the relationships, the second graph shows improvement from the former.  Scores for schools who have higher concentrations of economically disadvantaged kids are higher here than before. Low-income students are jeopardized in school systems that do not account for gains. When we move towards gains-based models, low income students have more room to grow and succeed.  While the difference is not much, the impact that even a small difference in slope can make is profound, which points to the overall success of the new program.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/sps2b.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This relationship becomes even more clear when you explore this map. Click on this map and you can explore specific schools. One school is Cecil Picard elementary school. Cecil Picard has a rate of 50% socioeconomically disadvantaged students. In the old system, their score is a 107, in the new adjusted system a 215. When these scores go up they make a difference:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;520&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://lascencio.carto.com/builder/c8976366-0042-4d2f-9795-aebc95a25f3b/embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; oallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; msallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;520&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://lascencio.carto.com/builder/ef0f2d88-56d8-41ab-bedb-1ef709df36ed/embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; oallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; msallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;p&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;School accountability scores have had a historic impact the future success of children.  The No Child Left Behind Act of 2002 mandates that federal funding be doled out according to the accountability scores of schools .  The argument here, as told by the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.stlouisfed.org/publications/regional-economist/april-2004/tough-lesson-more-mone%20%20y-doesnt-help-schools-accountability-does&quot;&gt;Federal Reserve of St. Louis&lt;/a&gt;, is that this will incentivize schools to be competitive and ensure that children are actually learning in order to get funding that helps the school as a whole.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Getting this funding is important to the future success of their students.  A study done by Northwestern University shows several positive takeaways from getting more school funding.  One positive outcome of getting federal funding is that graduation rates increase for every 10 percent more that schools are able to spend per student.  A second point the study made was that spending an additional 10 percent per student in schools has been linked to increased earning potential of students once they transition into adulthood. Adults who experience this increase in school funding on average earn 7 percent more and are 3 percent less likely to experience poverty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low-income students benefit the most from these outcomes, &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ipr.northwestern.edu/publications/policy-briefs/school-spending-policy-research-brief-Jackson.pdf&quot;&gt;Northwestern University’s study&lt;/a&gt; suggests.  They can earn up to 13 percent more and their families over time can increase their earning potential by 17 percent.  This means that not only are the immediate outcomes beneficial to students, but the funding received as a result of the school accountability rating system can influence individual outcomes in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One other thing to consider is that when schools have better ratings, better teachers soon follow.  In a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/news/education/wp/2015/09/01/new-analysis-argues-that-better-teachers-are-flocking-to-better-schools/?utm_term=.10ecc2a2733e&quot;&gt;2014 study&lt;/a&gt; of New York public schools, researchers found that teachers with better ratings tended to be attracted to schools who were improving their scores or already had higher scores.  This means that schools with lower ratings risk not having a good teaching staff to help children succeed in school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Schools are not just places children benefit from in the future.  For some low-income students in particular, school is a place to get away from the issues they are facing in their home lives.  In a &lt;a href=&quot;http://scholarworks.sjsu.edu/cgi/viewcontent.cgi?article=8150&amp;amp;context=etd_theses&quot;&gt;case study&lt;/a&gt; about the success stories of low-income students across the country, a student referred to as Jen talks about how “school was [her] sanctuary”, which allowed her to build confidence in her abilities and gave her the tools to succeed in the future, despite the struggles she faced at home.  Making sure schools like Jen’s have funding is important to making sure students have an alternative environment in which to grow and get a break from what they are experiencing in their personal lives.  Without this, their outcomes might not be as positive down the road.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, the changes in the Louisiana school rating system to try to improve their scores and the ability of students to succeed also gives them a better chance of securing better faculty.  Better teachers can then facilitate better scores from students because they are learning in a better environment, which could attract more qualified teachers. This cycle is one way that changing the school rating system can benefit the children in the Louisiana school system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall, the changes made to the Louisiana school accountability rating system have allowed students the opportunity to see their education improve, which will benefit them later in life.  More importantly, low-income students who did not perform as well under the old system are able to improve under the new gains-based system. Louisiana schools are looking up, and because of their strides made in education, so are the futures of the children they educate.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 16:15:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/louisiana-schools/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/louisiana-schools/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Food Deserts in Baltimore, Maryland Linked to Historical Racial Discrimination and Lower Life Expectancies</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The ability to purchase and consume fresh and healthy foods is often taken for granted.  In the United States, millions of people in low-income, minority, and/or rural areas live in food deserts, which the Centers for Disease Control and Prevention defines as “areas that lack access to affordable fruits, vegetables, whole grains, low-fat milk, and other foods that make up a full and healthy diet.”  Baltimore, Maryland is no exception.  Past discriminatory policies such as redlining have continued to perpetuate disparities in health and wealth.  Food deserts in Baltimore disproportionately affect low-income people of color who, because of shortages in healthy food options, suffer the indirect and direct consequences and continue to live in a cycle of poor health and poverty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Johns Hopkins recently concluded that, in Baltimore city, 146,077 residents or 23.5 percent of residents, live in food deserts.  Of this population, 124,521 are African American.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1934, the Federal Housing Administration (FHA), created by the Federal Housing Act of 1934, introduced the discriminatory and unethical practice of “redlining.”  Between 1934 and 1968, the FHA would assess neighborhoods, issuing grades between A (green) and D (red) and consistently rating the neighborhoods with African Americans as lower grades.  African Americans and residents of these redlined districts were explicitly refused mortgage loans, among other financial services, by the FHA.  This discrimination decreased the values of homes in low-graded areas and drove away businesses and wealthy and/or white individuals.  Despite being deemed illegal and unethical, redlining continues to affect African Americans today as many face the repercussions of family and neighborhoods being “D-rated” nearly a century ago.  Below is the 1937 Residential Security Map of Baltimore city paired with a 2017 Map of African American populations in Baltimore city.  The 2017 map is broken down by “community statistical areas,” clusters of neighborhoods zoned by the city government to better gather data associated to population health.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
  &lt;tbody&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;1937&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;2017&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/red_map.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Admitting some movement within the African American population, much of the pattern remains.  Throughout the years, this discrimination has caused businesses, such as supermarkets, to be less willing to build in historically low-rated neighborhoods.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The map below outlines the locations of grocery stores in relation to African American population as well as median household income and life expectancy at birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;520&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; src=&quot;https://fymontalto.carto.com/builder/3fa7035a-077c-4732-bddd-142b5dc5e0ca/embed&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; webkitallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; mozallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; oallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot; msallowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The locations of full grocery stores, including large chains such as Safeway and Giant, appear to be most associated with community statistical areas with lower African American populations and, inevitably, higher median household incomes and lower life expectancies at birth.  Limited and small grocery stores, including smaller chains with less reliable fresh foods, appear to fit a similar pattern, although are more likely to be located in a community statistical area with high African American populations and lower median household incomes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The scatter plots below exemplify the relationship between African American populations and median household income as well as life expectancy at birth.  The greater the African American population in a community statistical area, the lower the median household income and the lower the life expectancy at birth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/baltimore_scatter1.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/baltimore_scatter2.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place matters.  Yolanda Bowman, a graduating master’s student and nurse at University of Maryland, Baltimore, says, “Access to healthy food, like fresh fruit and vegetables, is a very big challenge for inner city low-income Baltimore residents who have very limited transportation” and no grocery stores within walking distance of their homes.  “The only choices these residents have are fast-food restaurants, liquor stores, and convenience marts,” Bowman remarks.  These locations often only sell processed foods with long shelf-lives, foods that are high in sodium, cholesterols, sugar, and other ingredients that contribute to health problems such as diabetes, obesity, and, eventually, lower life expectancy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Low-income African American residents in Baltimore face a cycle of poverty that is nearly impossible to escape.  With little expendable income, these residents lack transportation to supermarkets with fresh and health foods.  They are more likely to shop at corner stores, such as fast-food restaurants and convenience marts, which may be more expensive as they are less likely to take government food stamps and more likely to cause health problems and medical bills.  Low-income African Americans remain in the cycle of poverty.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the past year, Baltimore government and neighborhood officials have made efforts to improve the availability of fresh and healthy foods.  Last June, Saché Jones and Myeasha Taylor of Two Moons Food Group opened a farmer’s market in the parking lot of 1400 Greenmount Ave, located on the map between Midtown and Greenmount East community statistical areas.  Jones, a resident of Baltimore city, explained to Baltimore Magazine that people “sometimes travel as long as 30 to 40 minutes to get to a grocery store that has the freshest produce.”  After conducting a door-to-door survey, Jones and Taylor concluded that local residents want grocery stores with healthy and fresh foods within reasonable walking distance from their homes.  The farmer’s market has been considered successful and will continue this summer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Early this year, Mayor Catherine Pugh announced the rebranding of “food deserts,” declaring “healthy food priority areas” to be a more relevant and accurate term that depicts the role of the government moving forward.  Pugh told that Baltimore Sun that “Deserts’ implies there is no food, when actually there is an imbalance between healthy and unhealthy foods.”
This imbalance is caused by social inequalities as much as it leads to social inequalities.  Baltimore, Maryland will continue to make efforts to address these inequalities in order to eliminate food deserts, improve life expectancy at birth, and eliminate endless cycles of poverty and poor health.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 15:57:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/food-deserts/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/food-deserts/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The New Housing Crisis</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The District of Columbia is currently experiencing an economic boom unlike any other in its history; but is it leaving long-time residents behind?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Trena Taylor was born and raised in Shaw, much like most native Washingtonians, she grew up in a two story colorful walk up townhouse on Bates street. She had gone to Dunbar High School, only 5 blocks away,  and graduated from there in the early eighties. Now, like many of her neighbors, she can no longer afford to live in the same house she grew up in, much less the same neighborhood. That’s because Shaw, which includes a part of the U street corridor, has gone from being known as the “black broadway” to the epicenter of gentrification and the affordable housing crisis in Washington, D.C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“It’s not the same; it feels like a different country.” Taylor tells me. The block where she grew up, was once filled with mom and pop owned shops and dinners. Where once middle class African-Americans could afford to live there, the area has now become one of the trendiest neighborhoods for young urban professionals. As a result, long-term residents have been displaced, many moving East of the River, into deep Northeast, Prince George county, Maryland, or even farther afield to Pennsylvania or North Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Taylor’s reason for leaving mirror these concerns. “The rent went up too much,” she says. Average rent prices had gone up by 3 percent year since 2000, in a city where units that are federally subsidized or built after 1975 are not eligible for rent-control.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But that’s not the only reason she left. “They treat like your less, like a second class citizen,” she said of the newcomers. Between the economic concerns, and the feeling of not belonging, the incentive for long-term African American residents to remain in the area is not there anymore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Harlem Renaissance poet Langston Hughes once wrote “I tried to write poems like the sad songs on Seventh Street” as he would listen to them in LeDroit park. Today, walking down around 7th and U,  one is more likely to find high-end condominiums, where rents start at $1,700, chic coffee shops and upscale restaurants than the sad songs that inspired Hughes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is because of the mass demographic change that Shaw has gone through. When Taylor was growing up in Shaw in the early 80’s it was a predominantly black, as the neighborhood went through one of the worst crime waves in the history of the city. However, by the turn of the century, as the city became safer and high-paying jobs moved back to the city from the Northern Virginia suburbs, things started to change.
Many developers, such as those of the Avalon, which owns three  residential buildings in D.C., claims that these concerns are outweighed by the benefites. According to them, many of the owners simply cashed out, and accepted the lump sums offered for homes which were once purchased at a fraction of the price.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the 20001 zip code, which covers most of Shaw and Bloomingdale, another adjacent neighborhood, along with a couple blocks downtown, the demographics went through a massive shift in the 2000s, a change that would leave the area looking very differently today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As more and more relatively wealthy white transplants moved in, incomes rose, so did rent and home prices. Today these neighborhoods look very differently than what they did 15 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All Data from the Census bureau, censusreporter.org&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/change_white.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/change_black.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 20001, the percentage of white people relative to black people living in the area shot up 9% to 46% in 2016. In 20009, which covers most of Adams Morgan, Columbia Heights and Meridian Hill Park, the amount of white people grew to 80%. In 20010, which covers Mount Pleasant and Park View, it doubled to 2/3rds of the population. And finally in 20003, Navy Yard and Capitol, the few parts of Southeast not east of the Anacostia river, whites also became the majority after doubling their size.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In all four of these zip codes, the white population grew substantially while the black population either stagnated or went down.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/change_pop.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This racial displacement has resulted in D.C. becoming one of the most segregated and unequal cities in America. The results are staggering: Ward 3, located entirely in Northwest, is 74 percent white and 6 percent black, the median income in is $112,000, the  86 percent of residents have a bachelor’s degree. Meanwhile, Ward 8, is 92 percent black and four percent white, the median income stands at $31,000 and only 14% have a bachelor’s degree. As such, the boom in the population has affected the groups differently&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/growth_pop.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;From the District of Columbia Office of Planning.and census bureau.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While the white population had grown in all wards except 7 &amp;amp; 8, the black population declined in all wards between 1990 and 2010. This reflects that even the wards East of the River are becoming too expensive for the districts long-term residents.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Anabelle Martinez of the Central American Resource Center, an immigration and housing advocacy group based in Columbia Heights, this in part is why the problem is hard for many people to understand. “When you directly benefit from something, it’s hard to see its downside,” she says. “Most people who move here don’t see the spaces where they are renting as places where people have lived for 10, 15, 20 years, but rather just a temporary home for yourself.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the clients at the center are Latino immigrants, mainly from El Salvador, who came to D.C. during the eighties. Many of them settled in the Mount Pleasant/Columbia Heights area, opening Spanish-language Catholic Churches, pupuserias, and grocery stores stocked with imports from their home countries.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The city will claim that the influx of relatively wealthy newcomers has led to a new tax base, which fills the coffers that pays for new services, a competent police force, and glitzy new public libraries and recreation centers. Developers say that rising home prices in the city have led to many older people cashing in on their homes and moving to the suburbs.
But for people Taylor and the clients of the Central American Resource Center, those are hollow words.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 15:28:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/dc-gentrification/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/dc-gentrification/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Unknown Future of Young Teachers</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;The field of education is struggling to find college students to become the next generation of teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flourish-embed&quot; data-src=&quot;visualisation/43237&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;The salaries of U.S. teachers has declined in 29 states since 1969 when adjusted for inflation. Low income is a main factor in why young people are not entering the field. Data Source: &lt;a href=&quot;https://nces.ed.gov/programs/digest/d17/tables/dt17_211.60.asp?current=yes&quot;&gt;National Education Association&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Adam Schasel stays up late, just like any other twenty-something econ major fresh out of college. But, Adam is writing lesson plans for his high school economics class in Nampa, Idaho where he arrived through Teach for America with no curriculum and 30 old textbooks. But young people like Adam are becoming harder to find.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fewer college students are pursuing teaching careers, according to studies conducted by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.act.org/content/dam/act/unsecured/documents/CCCR-2014-FutureEducators.pdf&quot;&gt;ACT and the Dept. of Education&lt;/a&gt;. Teaching shortages have plagued the nation as the demand for educators skyrocketed after the Great Recession. The U.S. school system is expected to grow by 3 million students in the next decade, but teaching program enrollments have dropped by 35 percent between 2009 and 2014, according to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf&quot;&gt;Learning Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The lack of interest in education is a cause for great concern in the field and at American University, students might not be aware of its benefits. A younger workforce would be more equipped with knowledge about modern technology and new teaching practices, but there is concern about teaching as a career among college students because of low salary, high workload, and a lack of respect. Teaching salaries have decreased in 29 states since 1969 when adjusted for inflation. Nationally, salaries have decreased 1.6 percent since that time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Learning about the lack of available teaching jobs in my field, the hostile environment, and the low pay really turned me off from becoming a teacher,” Salant said. “I haven’t ruled it out as a possibility in the future, but it will not be my primary career as I had once hoped.” C.H. Salant started American University in pursuit of a career in music education through composing and pedagogue. They now will start graduate school at AU for Arts Management.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Young educators are extremely beneficial to K-12 schools, according to American University professor, Traci Dennis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Younger teachers are great because they are willing to be innovative and creative and come with a stronger technology background,” Dennis said. “They tend to be more innovative because the way they’ve been taught in college. There are different engagement in classrooms that university professors might be using… that gives a lot of value to a younger teaching force.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-53n8D&quot; src=&quot;https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/53n8D/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;400&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;if(&quot;undefined&quot;==typeof window.datawrapper)window.datawrapper={};window.datawrapper[&quot;53n8D&quot;]={},window.datawrapper[&quot;53n8D&quot;].embedDeltas={&quot;100&quot;:528,&quot;200&quot;:442,&quot;300&quot;:426,&quot;400&quot;:400,&quot;500&quot;:400,&quot;700&quot;:400,&quot;800&quot;:400,&quot;900&quot;:400,&quot;1000&quot;:400},window.datawrapper[&quot;53n8D&quot;].iframe=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-53n8D&quot;),window.datawrapper[&quot;53n8D&quot;].iframe.style.height=window.datawrapper[&quot;53n8D&quot;].embedDeltas[Math.min(1e3,Math.max(100*Math.floor(window.datawrapper[&quot;53n8D&quot;].iframe.offsetWidth/100),100))]+&quot;px&quot;,window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(&quot;undefined&quot;!=typeof a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var b in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])if(&quot;53n8D&quot;==b)window.datawrapper[&quot;53n8D&quot;].iframe.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][b]+&quot;px&quot;});&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Starting salary for teachers is less of a cause for concern in DC. By completing a full-time student-teaching position in the spring of their senior year, Elementary and Secondary Education students at American University graduate with a DC teaching license with reciprocity in 40 other states. The District has the highest starting teaching salary in the country, at $53,601 with just a Bachelor’s degree, compared to $38,371 nationally.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Dennis’ class, Schools and Society, students discuss a myriad of issues facing K-12 schools, including Common Core state standards, integration and segregation, school finance, and culturally relevant pedagogy to give future teachers a solid foundation of education’s role in society.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We talk about the whole idea of innovation and how schools haven’t changed much over the years,” Dennis said. “Are schools really prepared for the needs of 21st century learners?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The answer is, most K-12 schools are not. This is due to lack of funds and resources. But young teachers could help bridge the gap. College students like Schasel, who have the calling to make a difference, might become interested in education too late in their degree to switch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students recruited for programs for TFA typically study business or art and have to undergo a six week crash course without a solid foundation in education pedagogy. Teachers with little preparation leave the position at rates two to three times higher than their peers with a more comprehensive education, &lt;a href=&quot;https://learningpolicyinstitute.org/sites/default/files/product-files/A_Coming_Crisis_in_Teaching_REPORT.pdf&quot;&gt;according to the Learning Policy Institute&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Dept. of Education launched the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.teach.org/&quot;&gt;“Teach”&lt;/a&gt; campaign in 2013 to fill one million potentially vacant positions formerly held by baby boomers. They wanted to replace them with the nation’s top performing college students. Former secretary of education, Arne Duncan, said to the &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2013/11/21/education/campaign-seeks-to-recruit-top-students-to-become-teachers.html&quot;&gt;NYTimes&lt;/a&gt; that he wanted “very, very high caliber college graduates to come and work in our nation’s schools.” The Teach websites acts as a search engine and customized portal for future teachers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe id=&quot;datawrapper-chart-CzUqY&quot; src=&quot;https://datawrapper.dwcdn.net/CzUqY/1/&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowtransparency=&quot;true&quot; style=&quot;width: 0; min-width: 100% !important;&quot; height=&quot;311&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;if(&quot;undefined&quot;==typeof window.datawrapper)window.datawrapper={};window.datawrapper[&quot;CzUqY&quot;]={},window.datawrapper[&quot;CzUqY&quot;].embedDeltas={&quot;100&quot;:415,&quot;200&quot;:363,&quot;300&quot;:337,&quot;400&quot;:337,&quot;500&quot;:311,&quot;700&quot;:311,&quot;800&quot;:311,&quot;900&quot;:311,&quot;1000&quot;:311},window.datawrapper[&quot;CzUqY&quot;].iframe=document.getElementById(&quot;datawrapper-chart-CzUqY&quot;),window.datawrapper[&quot;CzUqY&quot;].iframe.style.height=window.datawrapper[&quot;CzUqY&quot;].embedDeltas[Math.min(1e3,Math.max(100*Math.floor(window.datawrapper[&quot;CzUqY&quot;].iframe.offsetWidth/100),100))]+&quot;px&quot;,window.addEventListener(&quot;message&quot;,function(a){if(&quot;undefined&quot;!=typeof a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])for(var b in a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;])if(&quot;CzUqY&quot;==b)window.datawrapper[&quot;CzUqY&quot;].iframe.style.height=a.data[&quot;datawrapper-height&quot;][b]+&quot;px&quot;});&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When compared to other popular entry level jobs for AU graduates, a starting teaching salary in D.C. fares pretty well. But since growth for salaries are so stagnant across the nation, it limits oppportunities for undergrads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“In general, I have been hesitant about pursuing education because I do not believe it would be able to sufficiently help in paying off my student loans,” American University Class of 2017 alumni, Naomi Ziegler, said, “I believe in the value and importance of our educators but I also strongly believe that we, as a nation, do not recognize them or their contributions to the degree they deserve.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At a university that is orientated around public service, Dennis said she thinks attracting more students to the Education program earlier in their studies will boost enrollment. She is creating a cadre of her students to will help lead campus presentations about the benefits of graduating with an Education degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Students like sophomore Michaela Desimone feel that teaching is about connecting to young people as their mentor. Desimone decided to study Secondary Education and History at American after taking Schools in Society and falling in love with the field. She hopes to pursue a Master’s in Special Education after graduating too. After visiting many local schools in D.C. and speaking to their special education teachers, she felt connected back to her own experiences in those classrooms from elementary through high school.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Desimone doesn’t deny that teaching in America today comes with some concerns, especially around issues of gun control following shootings in Parkland, Fla. and Newtown, Conn.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“You would think that a teacher’s job is the most safe, but in this day and age it isn’t for some reason,” Desimone said. “It’s a conversation that needs to be had. Difficult conversations are a part of being an educator. A teacher is a second parent, a moral guidance, a role model.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Only five percent of the 1.85 million high schools students who &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ewa.org/blog-educated-reporter/what-happens-when-young-people-dont-want-be-teachers&quot;&gt;took the ACT&lt;/a&gt; in 2014 indicated they wanted a career as an educator, down from seven percent in 2010.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There needs to be a broader cultural emphasis on the importance of education,” Schasel said. “The best thing about TFA is that every day I feel like I’m in some weird Parks-and-Rec-style organization of young, motivated people who want to make a difference in their communities. If we could get young people to look outside the confines of big cities, I think they’d find a lot of opportunities to make a lasting impact in public education.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/teacher_distribution.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Public schools have the lowest percentage of teachers under the age of 30. This means that students likely have less access to new innovative teaching ideas. Data Source: US Dept. of Education&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Public schools today have the lowest percentage of teachers younger than 30 years old. About half of those who complete teacher preparation programs are hired to teach in a classroom, showing the lack of co-ordination between schools of education and identifying what &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ecs.org/wp-content/uploads/Teacher-Shortages-What-We-Know.pdf&quot;&gt;the actual market demands&lt;/a&gt;. In Prince George’s County alone, there are currently 1,400 teaching vacancies, according to Dennis. Colleges and training programs will need to strategize with K-12 schools to fill specific vacant spots and fill those spots first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The U.S. Dept. of Education tracks &lt;a href=&quot;https://www2.ed.gov/about/offices/list/ope/pol/bteachershortageareasreport201718.pdf&quot;&gt;teacher shortages&lt;/a&gt; in each state as a tool to deploy financial resources to the areas with the most dire need for educators. This also results in recommendations for where Teach for America sends their corps members, often in high poverty, high minority schools. But the need for teachers is everywhere. All but two U.S. states reported teacher shortages in 2015, especially in the fields of special education, science and mathematics. Some states have even begun recruitment for teachers internationally, like in Arizona where schools have sponsored work visas for teachers &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/05/02/us/arizona-teachers-philippines.html?hp&amp;amp;action=click&amp;amp;pgtype=Homepage&amp;amp;clickSource=story-heading&amp;amp;module=second-column-region&amp;amp;region=top-news&amp;amp;WT.nav=top-news&quot;&gt;from the Philippines&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Nothing actually deterred me from teaching, I simply found a ‘true-er’ calling,” Steph Black, a junior formerly in the School of Education, said. She witnessed the Supreme Court hearing for Whole Women’s Health v Texas by volunteering for NARAL Pro-Choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I listened to something like five straight hours of pro-choice, progressive speakers and knew in my heart that that was what I was meant to do-advocate for women and feminism on a large scale,” she said. “Being one woman in a classroom with 30 kids wasn’t the right kind of impact I wanted to have.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And no, teaching is not for every college student. But institutes of higher education need to improve recruiting and promotion techniques to boost interest in this field. While the teaching has surely changed in the last ten years, it doesn’t mean that more inspired teachers won’t be needed to make the change for education in the future.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“What really pushed me over the edge was the realization that I could always come back to work in DC no matter what happened – I would never have another opportunity to drop everything and take a giant leap of faith to try and enact positive social change,” Schasel said. “Since then I’ve met so many remarkable people who are really dedicating themselves to education.”&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 14:45:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/young-teachers/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/young-teachers/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Large Gaps Between Medicare Spending and Enrollment May Prompt Changes in the System</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Certain regions in the United States adhere to the trend that the spending rate on Medicare is higher than the enrollment rate. On average, Midwestern states have the largest gap between how much is spent on Medicare and how many people are enrolling in the program. In contrast, Southern states on average have the smallest gap between money spent on Medicare and amount of enrollees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Medicare is a government program that provides health insurance for Americans aged 65 years and older. These individuals receive the benefits of Medicare through paying taxes into the system as they work. Depending on their plan, recipients have to pay a monthly premium as well as a copay for services received. The amount of money recipients have to pay for these services depends on a variety of factors, including those specific to region.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Health care in Nevada is different than health care in Washington D.C.,” said Deputy Assistant Secretary in the Federal Housing Administration Office of Health Care, Roger Lukoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sue Keating, a Medicare recipient, experienced these differences when she moved from Mississippi to Las Vegas. Under her plan in Mississippi, Keating said she would have had an expensive copay for her hip replacement, but in Las Vegas, she didn’t pay anything for the procedure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“They [hospital bills] are thousands of dollars that we don’t have,” Keating, who receives Medicare services through United Healthcare with the American Association of Retired Persons, said. “We’re completely satisfied with what we got.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Las Vegas, located in Clark County, has some of the best health plans, according to a United Healthcare sales associate. With United Healthcare, different states have different plans due to these regional differences.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although some of these differences are paid by the Medicare recipients through their premiums and copays, the bulk of the bill is paid for by Medicare and insurance companies. “I’m very fortunate right now that I don’t have to pay when I go for procedures. Medicare covers a lot and whatever they don’t cover, my insurance company handles,” said Maryann Tydryszewski, a Medicare recipient in New Jersey.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The majority of Midwestern states have the largest gap between enrollee rates and Medicare spending rates. Out of this region, South Dakota and Minnesota have the largest gaps between these two factors. Between 2013 and 2014, South Dakota’s spending on Medicare increased 6.9%, while their enrollment only increased 3%. This makes the gap between spending and enrollment about 3.7%. In Minnesota, spending on Medicare increased 6.8% and enrollment increased 2.9%. This results in a gap of 3.8%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/medicare_chart.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contrasting the large gap in those Western states, the Southern region contains some of the smallest gaps between Medicare spending and enrollment numbers. Louisiana and North Carolina are the two Southern states with the smallest gap. Between 2013 and 2014, Louisiana had a 2.9% increase in total spending and a 2.8% increase in enrollment, leaving them with the smallest gap, 0.1%, between spending and enrollment. North Carolina had a 3.6% increase in total spending and a 3.4% increase in enrollment, making their gap a low 0.2%.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There may be multiple explanations for this phenomena, including more complicated patients seeking care,” said Lukoff after observing this trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the number of Medicare patients with complicated health concerns increases, there is a rise in the number of expensive treatments. The result is the government spending more money on Medicare. This increase in spending also coincides with increased enrollment rates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flourish-embed&quot; data-src=&quot;visualisation/39935&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The disparities between the Southern region’s spending and enrollment compared to those of the West’s puts forth the question: what motivates these regional disparities?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Different prices may be due to regional differences, level of care, if it’s specialty care, rural, or has less facilities,” Debbie Feierman, an employee at the Centers for Medicare and Medicaid Services, said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One of the factors that influences regional differences is the amount of specialized facilities in different states, according to Lukoff. Medicare recipients that require uncommon procedures often have to go to states with specialized health centers and medical schools to receive treatment. Because these services are expensive, Medicare pays more money in those states per capita.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of these specialized health care centers and medical schools are located on the East coast. New York and Philadelphia, specifically, are known for their expensive health care, according to Lukoff.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;500&quot; height=&quot;300&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; src=&quot;https://fusiontables.google.com/embedviz?q=select+col2%3E%3E0+from+1XHvp-jNIUFx5ySIvolWj3jU4mpRyZxFlHXRyV5FZ&amp;amp;viz=MAP&amp;amp;h=false&amp;amp;lat=41.50513428809335&amp;amp;lng=-94.75936999999999&amp;amp;t=1&amp;amp;z=3&amp;amp;l=col2%3E%3E0&amp;amp;y=2&amp;amp;tmplt=2&amp;amp;hml=KML&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other factors for the increase in Medicare spending include a growing Medicare population as baby boomers age and their increase in life expectancy, according to State Senator Valerie Wiener (Retired) of Nevada, who is now a medicare recipient herself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Increasing costs of healthcare have been in the political conversation as they are expected to rise to almost 20% of the GDP by 2026, according to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.cms.gov/Research-Statistics-Data-and-Systems/Statistics-Trends-and-Reports/NationalHealthExpendData/Downloads/ForecastSummary.pdf&quot;&gt;a CMS report&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We don’t have a budget. In our country we don’t know how much we spent until the year’s over, well after the year’s over,”  Lukoff said. “That’s why our costs are almost 20%. Congress likes to say yes to almost as many things as they can.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flourish-embed&quot; data-src=&quot;visualisation/43307&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As healthcare consumes more of the country’s spending, other government services, such as education, are facing cutbacks, according to Wiener.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Where is the tipping point where medicare is depleting other services enough were we have to have the hard conversation about revitalizing the system?” Wiener said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the cost of healthcare continuously grows in the US, there’s been discussions about moving the age of eligibility for Medicare up from 65 to 67. This has been met with opposition from current and soon-to-be Medicare recipients.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“There’s two things old people do. They vote, and they love Medicare,” Lukoff said. The high turn out rate for the group of 65 makes Medicare a top priority for politicians to consider.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Keating acknowledged fears amongst her peers that Medicare will run out of funds. “If we didn’t have Medicare, we wouldn’t seek treatment.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There remains a tension between the increasing cost of healthcare for the government and the desires of the people to keep Medicare.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I have enough bills to pay and I don’t have to worry about health coverage, people who don’t have this neglect to go to the doctors and don’t get medicine,” Tydryszewski said, “I feel bad for those people that aren’t covered.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 14:37:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/medicare-spending/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/medicare-spending/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Get to know more about the hidden side of Online dating</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;About 2 decades ago, when online-dating just came out in 1995, no one had ever thought of how popular online-dating would become, nor did they know how dangerous it could be. Nowadays, more singles are starting to date or hook up by using online-dating apps, such as Tinder and Grindr. However, more and more horrifying crimes had been linked to online-dating app usages in recent years, like being killed by their Tinder dates when meeting offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As one of the most popular online-dating apps, Tinder was initially released in 2012, which was around 5 years ago. By 2014, Tinder, the first “swiping apps”, whose users employ a swiping motion to choose photos of users, was registering about one billion “swipes” per day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to research from Eharmony.com, 40 percent of Americans use online-dating, and men make up 52.4 percent of online-dating users in comparison to the rest 47.6 percent who are women. A survey by global research agency shows that 20 percent of women admitted to using an older photo from when they were younger and thinner, while 40 percent of men said they lied about their jobs in an effort to sound more successful. With such a high percentage of fake information, it is hard to tell who whose online strangers really are, and how to protect our safety and privacy, while also be able to communicate and interact with other interesting dates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Sydney Loofe, 24, met Balley Boswell on Tinder and was excited for her first date with Boswell on November 15, 2017 and posted photos after her getting ready on snapchat with the caption, “Ready for my date.”. She was found missing the second day after her date. Half a month later, Loofe’s body was found in a rural area, dismembered. This is a very recent crime case that is related to Tinder usage, but this is not the only case that happened.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Francia Ruth Ibarra was killed by her tinder date, Bocangegra, and her body was dissolved in acid. Before she was murdered by Bocangegra, they had actually gone on several dates. The police believed that Ibarra maybe have turned down Bocangegra’s sexual advance, which may lead to his later cruel murdering.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is no study showing that the app itself leads to any sort of abuse. However the app users were exposed more to people who are sexually coercive. At the same time the open online environment could lull users into assuming they know someone they met on the app after some conversations, therefore making themselves more unprotected and vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to a survey conducted by ABODO.com about how 3500 college students are using dating apps, there are some very interesting data. Only 4 percent of participants prefer to use apps to meet potential dates and 27 percent had reported been harassed on APPS. While 35.5 percent of female participants and 14.1 percent of male participants said they had been harassed.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/harassed.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In order to find out if t¬¬here are any unpleasant experience they have ever had when using Tinder, 100 students in American University had answered the survey. When analyzing the data collected from the survey, an interesting finding that was shown in the survey implies that 4 percent of the participants has been blackmailed by their Tinder dates, 22 percent had received obscene languages or photos, 35 percent had experienced offensive languages and 8 percent has found mismatches in their date’s profile after meeting offline.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;unpleasant-tinder-experiences-among-american-university-students&quot;&gt;Unpleasant Tinder experiences among American University students&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/datingpie1.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Pew Research center found that between 2008 to 2013, the proportion of American adults using dating service tripled. In Britain, the reported crimes and attacks related to online dating increased 6 times over 2009 to 2014, which was about the same period. If US and UK are experiencing the similar trends, dating APPs users should be more cautious about the hidden danger behind the screen. A report from National Crime Agency showed that 85 percentage of victims are females and victims from 20 to 24 and 25 to 29 have the highest numbers of been attacked. These numbers are serious warnings to online dating APPs users that they should be more careful about their online dates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/datingtime.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/datingchart2.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nathaniel Worthman, a freshman student working part time at CLEAR center in American University said that, “I never really had any awful experiences. I met some pretty great people on Tinder,” when asking about how he thought of Tinder, “I think it’s good because you get to meet a lot of people that you wouldn’t typically get to meet in daily life. I feel like my life been a lot better because I’ve meet more different kinds of people.” However, there are also some students that have negative impression to Tinder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“A lot of people on ‘hook-up apps’ such as Tinder and Bumble will pretend to be ‘single and is ready to mingle’, and what they really want to do is to hook up,” said Lauren Monahan, a freshman student in American University, “Another thing is, a lot of them are already in couple, so they have a boyfriend or girlfriend already and they are actually cheating on them.” Monahan said that she has heard of these a lot from her friends and that is the major reason that she knew about why people lied in Tinder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For me, I don’t really go on for the hooking up aspect, I usually just talk to people and never do anything. A big turnoff for me is if they all look very good, and you swipe up to read their profile and they have nothing there, and you’re like ‘this is just a guy who wants to hook-up, swipe left.’ “said Monahan on how she found out what kind of profile she should not trust when using Tinder.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chenhui Xu, a sophomore student in American University said that he has experienced mismatches on profile pictures when meeting up with the girls he knew from Tinder. “When I met them, I just realized how big the differences are between their pictures and their real persons. I have a lot of friend who heavily photoshopped their profile pictures on Tinder, so I have lost my trust in those profile pictures that I have seen on Tinder.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the development of the technology, the internet continues to mold the global culture of romance, and users should be much more careful when using these app. Not only the users should protect their privacy and safety more, the industry should fight with the dark side of online-dating and provide more armor against it in order to create a more peaceful and harmonious environment.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 14:31:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/online-dating/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/online-dating/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>What is causing the local and national rise in hate crimes?</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Two men were beaten in the U Street area downtown in an attack on April 15, which is suspected to be a sexual orientation-based hate crime and just one of several that have occurred so far this year, according to Metropolitan Police Department.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite an overall decline in citywide crime rates in the last year, hate crimes increased nearly 70 percent between 2016 and 2017. Authorities say that multiple variables are responsible for the spike.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“These may be crimes that have been occurring throughout time, but we are now doing a better job of getting people to report, getting our officers to recognize them and, quite honestly, classifying our reports properly,” said Brett Parson, lieutenant and commanding officer for the MPD’s Special Liaison Branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;MPD defines a hate crime as a motive for a crime which demonstrates an accused person’s prejudice against a victim based off perceived or actual factors, such as race or religion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to MPD &lt;a href=&quot;https://mpdc.dc.gov/page/bias-related-crimes-hate-crimes-data&quot;&gt;data&lt;/a&gt;, the number of hate crimes committed based off of race and sexual orientation, among others, increased the most between 2016 and 2017, with the number of sexual orientation-based crimes rising 40 percent. Sexual orientation-based hate crimes accounted for nearly one-third of total hate crimes in 2017.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/hatechart1.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In looking at national hate crime data provided by the FBI, 2016 brought the highest number of hate crimes the nation had seen in five years, with more than 6,000 total biased-related crimes.
While national hate crime rates alternated between decreasing and increasing from 2011 to 2014, there was a spike from 2014 to 2015, which has continued through the most recent FBI data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;D.C. saw nearly an identical trend, beginning with an uptick in hate crimes starting in 2015 and continuing through 2017, with more than double the number of biased-related crimes in 2017 than in the years 2012 to 2015, respectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/hatechart2.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
In 2016, there were more than 25 hate crimes per 100,000 residents in D.C.,
according to data from MPD and the U.S. Census Bureau.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/hatechart3.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
Recent national data, according to the FBI, shows an upward trend in overall hate crimes despite years of back and forth decreasing and increasing at the beginning of the decade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We respond to bias-related crimes in the District with a robust response,” said Parson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With regards to the most recent LGBT hate crime in the U Street area, Parson said that the lead detective is still investigating the case. He said that community involvement will be vital in solving this case, like many other biased-related crimes in D.C., as recent video &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.washingtonpost.com/local/public-safety/video-is-released-in-assault-seen-as-potential-hate-crime/2018/04/16/0217fd3c-41c7-11e8-bba2-0976a82b05a2_story.html?utm_term=.57895729bfa6&quot;&gt;footage&lt;/a&gt; of the assault released by MPD shows many civilians in the area at the time of the attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“That means that community members are going to be the key to solving this case,” he said, “Because someone was there that has information or someone knows someone that was there that can encourage them to come forward.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;help-from-the-community-for-the-community&quot;&gt;Help from the community, for the community&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The D.C. Anti-Violence Project (DC AVP), a volunteer-based &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thedccenter.org/programs_dcavp.html&quot;&gt;organization&lt;/a&gt;, aims to reduce violence against members of the LGBT community through advocacy, survivor support and encouraging victims to report hate crimes committed against them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to Stephania Mahdi, 38, co-chair of DC AVP, there has been more activism through the organization. She said that #MeToo and other national movements have created a platform where activism against general LGBT bias is more widespread.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We’re seeing more awareness toward more marginalized groups that are getting a voice,” said Mahdi.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Shannon Quinn, 23, is a communications coordinator for DC AVP. She said that she has noticed an increase in tension across the city since the 2016 election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“Every day is stressful and kind of fearful for a lot of people,” said Quinn with regards to the recent uptick in hate crimes in D.C.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since bringing on a full-time social worker, Mahdi said that there have been more members of the LGBT community seeking support and resources from DC AVP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parson said that MPD is taking steps to improve relations between law enforcement and members of the community too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The purpose of liaison units, such as the LGBT Liaison Unit, is to give support to communities who are underserved and lack a strong relationship with law enforcement. The units are made up of officers who are members and allies of the respective communities they serve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The real concept behind the liaison units is a different way of engaging and building relationships with the citizens that live, work and visit the District of Columbia,” said Parson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;2018-bias-related-crime-projections&quot;&gt;2018 bias-related crime projections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;According to 2018 hate crime data as of March 31, bias related incidents based on sexual orientation, race and gender identity and expression are all up. The year-to-date data shows that race related hate crimes have doubled, gender identity and expression-based crimes are up eight from five and sexual orientation-based crimes have increased by two in the 2018 year-to-date numbers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Parson said that he believes that various changes over the last several years have contributed to the department’s ability to properly handle bias related-crimes and getting them reported properly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We reviewed our general orders and policies, we discussed how to ask questions, we discussed how to actually fill out the report,” said Parson.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He said that in order to determine whether the number of hate crimes is truly increasing, MPD can only look at the data and anecdotal information they have at hand.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“We don’t know what the true answer is, because there’s not been really any scientific research into this,” said Parson.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 13:44:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/hate-crimes/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/hate-crimes/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Remembering the Confederacy is not just for the states that were part of it</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;At the Jefferson Davis Historic Site in Fairview, Kentucky, stands a monument and a museum honoring the birthplace of the first – and only – president of the Confederate States of America. Photo courtesy of Roadside America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.roadsideamerica.com/attract/images/ky/KYFAIdavis_ks02_art1_620x300.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Near the southwest corner of Kentucky, there is a Washington Monument look-alike. At 351 feet, the obelisk is the tallest structure in Fairview. When it was constructed in 1924, it was the tallest structure in Kentucky. The obelisk, which sits on a base of solid Kentucky limestone, commemorates one of the state’s most famous sons: Jefferson Davis, president of the former Confederate States of America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Hodgenville, a town in the heart of Kentucky, the “First Lincoln Memorial” sits honoring the birthplace of Abraham Lincoln, the 16th president of the United States of America.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With 51 confederate sites, Kentucky, perhaps better than any other state, represents the parallel histories of the United States. In 2017, border states removed three times as many confederate monuments than former union states and states that were territories during the Civil War combined.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the Civil War, which split the country into North, South, and in-between from 1861 to 1865, Kentucky was one of five border states caught in the middle of the conflict.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even today, people still feel the tension between northern and southern ideologies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a gross oversimplification to say that everyone in the South remembers the people-owning days of the Confederacy fondly as much as it is an oversimplification to say that the northern states were unbigoted, moral beacons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a fair assessment, however, to say that the War Between the States was fought over the issue of slavery. The North wanted to abolish it. The South wanted to preserve it. That is the Confederacy’s legacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some say the men who fought for the Confederacy were heroes. Others call them racists and traitors. At what point does remembrance become reverence? In recent years, that point is being debated with greater ferocity after the Confederacy has been used to justify acts of violence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2015, self-proclaimed white supremacist Dylann Roof killed nine African-Americans in church in Charleston, South Carolina.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 2017, the “Unite the Right” rally in Charlottesville, Virginia resulted in the death a counter-protester and the injuries of several others when a member of the so-called alt-right drove his car into a crowd. The impetus of the “Unite the Right” rally was to protest the removal of a statue of Confederate Gen. Robert E. Lee from a park named for the same general.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Southern Poverty Law Center released in 2016 a list of all “public symbols of the Confederacy” found in the U.S. The symbols included monuments, towns, streets and schools but excluded historical sites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“For the final tally, the researchers excluded nearly 2,600 markers, battlefields, museums, cemeteries and other places or symbols that are largely historical in nature,” the SPLC said in their study of public Confederate symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a total of 135 symbols in the 19 states that were not members of the Confederacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;confederate-symbols&quot;&gt;Confederate symbols&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;flourish-embed&quot; data-src=&quot;story/6616&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;script src=&quot;https://public.flourish.studio/resources/embed.js&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be fair, this number is dwarfed in comparison to the number of public monuments to the former Confederate States of America that are densely scattered throughout the South. As of 2016, there were 1,354 symbols of the Confederacy in states that made up the Confederacy. Virginia, a former Confederate state, tops the list with 223 public Confederate symbols.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That is to be expected, especially given the majority of Civil War battles occurred in Southern states, particularly &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.civilwar.org/learn/articles/civil-war-facts&quot;&gt;Virginia and Tennessee&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, if these northern states, border states, and not-yet states fought against the Confederates on the Confederates’ own turf, why are Confederate monuments not confined to the battlegrounds and cities of the South?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That would only make sense on the grounds of remembering the nation’s history. After all you would not travel to Florida to remember the Alamo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some of these states have responded to the call to remove Confederate imagery from their cities. After the Charleston shooting, Kansas removed the Confederate battle flag from Wichita’s Veterans Park. In 2017, Baltimore removed all four of its Confederate statues overnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;After the removals, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.baltimoresun.com/news/maryland/baltimore-city/bs-md-ci-monuments-removed-20170816-story.html&quot;&gt;Baltimore Mayor Catherine Pugh&lt;/a&gt; said, “They needed to come down. My concern is for the safety and security of our people.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pugh feared Charlottesville-style violence. A group of protesters had threatened to tear down the statues of Lee and Gen. Thomas “Stonewall” Jackson themselves if action was not taken by the city.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A number of Confederate symbols were established by state and local governments. Two cities in California – Fort Bragg and Confederate Corners – are named for Confederate veterans despite California being Union state that never saw a Civil War battle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;From 1868 to the middle of the 1930s, Confederate monuments and memorials were going up on an almost yearly basis in Non-confederate states, the vast majority in Kentucky.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Half of the monuments standing in Non-confederate states today were erected before 1920.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During the fifty year period between 1868 and 1918, the United Daughters of the Confederacy and the Sons of Confederate Veterans were responsible for one-fourth of monuments and symbols in non-Confederate states.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The early 20th century in the U.S. saw two things: the 50th anniversary of the Civil War and the rise of Jim Crow, a brutal age of racial terror. In their analysis of Confederate symbols, the SPLC saw a correlation between the increases in construction of Confederate monuments and period of Jim Crow that terrorized African-Americans in an effort to maintain white supremacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The United Daughters of the Confederacy worked to erect a number of monuments to the Confederacy, but have since attempted to distance themselves from the violent white supremacists who use the same monuments to justify racism as history.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The president general of the United Daughters of the Confederacy wrote in a press release shortly after the rally in Charlottesville, “We are grieved that certain hate groups have taken the Confederate flag and other symbols as their own. Our members are the ones who, like our statues, have stayed quietly in the background, never engaging in public controversy.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teresa Roane, the archivist and librarian for the United Daughters of the Confederacy, said though she could not speak for her organization, it was important to know, “I’m a UDC member and I’m black.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Each person gets to make his or her own decision about how to remember history. Like Roane insisted, Confederate monuments can be war memorials, too. The best way to remember history is to remember it truthfully without heroes and without excuses.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 11:38:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/confederate_statues/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/confederate_statues/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Despite Record Low Crime Rates, Cuomo announces $18 Million for Gang Violence Prevention</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;WASHINGTON– Suffolk County announced record low crime rates during the first quarter of 2018. At the same time, Governor Cuomo approved $18 million for gang violence prevention on Long Island in the 2019 budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When President Donald Trump visited Brentwood during the summer of 2017, he spoke to a crowd of law enforcement officials and vowed to end MS-13 violence on Long Island. He described Long Island communities as “blood-stained killing fields” that are “under siege,” although some Long Island residents refuted his claim, including long-time resident Lisa Semivli.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite Trump’s worrisome rhetoric, the emergence of new gangs showed a slow decline from 2009 to 2012, and the number of gang-affiliated migrants entering the United States is even lower.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/gangcharts.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Source: National Gang Center. &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nationalgangcenter.gov/Survey-Analysis&quot;&gt;National Youth Gang Survey Analysis&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When looking at Suffolk County, President Trump’s claim about Long Island is still misleading. From 2009 to 2016, the total index crime, or overall crime rates, steadily declined. In the first quarter report of 2018, violent crime rates fell by more than 18 percent in Suffolk County, such as homicide, rape, and robbery. More drastically, gun violence fell by 49 percent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/scpdchart.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Source: Suffolk County Police Department, 2018&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite the steadily declining crime rates, Suffolk County Police associated more than a dozen homicides with the El Salvadoran gang MS-13 since January 2016. Of those cases, &lt;a href=&quot;https://cis.org/Report/Brentwood-NY-Consumed-MS13-Crime-Wave&quot;&gt;Brentwood&lt;/a&gt; saw nine murders, along with one attempted murder , and one rape of a teenager by the gang MS13 in 2016.&lt;br /&gt;
It’s unclear whether those arrested on suspicion of gang activity are identified through a specific gang marker or through detectives’ discretion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Governor Cuomo made &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ny.gov/programs/criminal-justice-reform-0&quot;&gt;criminal justice reform&lt;/a&gt; a focal point of his career. Since taking office, he pardoned 174 people. Last month, he announced a pro-bono legal service for immigrants in New York, combining volunteer lawyers with faith-based organizations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The program announced by Cuomo in April did not include funding for community outreach through faith-based organizations, although he did emphasize last month that this initiative would focus on preventative measures.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since Cuomo’s gubernatorial opponent, Cynthia Nixon (D-NY) announced her candidacy, she’s consistently attacked Cuomo for not being progressive enough. She was recently critical of the governor for not pursuing legislation to establish the entire state as a “sanctuary state.”
Following that attack, Cuomo &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nydailynews.com/news/politics/cynthia-nixon-vows-new-york-sanctuary-state-article-1.3917568&quot;&gt;responded&lt;/a&gt;, “I think we have the most progressive record in the country in this state.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He added that the $2 million for local law enforcement aid was for officers who already have a “difficult job.” Ms. Simivli argued that amount of money could be used better elsewhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/infographic.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Suffolk County Police officers have historically been paid the highest out of all 62 counties in New York, however, Newsday found that nearly 1,000 employees in 2017 received a &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.newsday.com/long-island/politics/suffolk-county-salary-200-000-nassau-1.17655983&quot;&gt;minimum salary&lt;/a&gt; of $200,000. That’s roughly the equivalent of 2,166 households working full-time last year, keeping in mind one household includes two full-time workers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Semivli said minority communities are also concerned about becoming a police state, where they may be “targeted.” She’s referring to Cuomo’s recent objections to ICE arrests throughout New York, where more than 200 “suspected undocumented immigrants.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“The police department in Suffolk is 2,500 active police, with only 65 being African American and 175 Latino,” said Semivli. “I think a minimum to be recruited for SCPD should be an Associate’s Degree also,” she added.
Both the African American and Hispanic communities are heavily underrepresented in local law enforcement. Ms. Semivli said she’d like to see an increase in diversity within SCPD, and the establishment of a diversity quota system within Suffolk County schools.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/race_police.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;“I don’t feel safe for my children or grandson because we are people of color. I feel that gangs are the result of a community forgetting about its youth and throwing them away,” said Semivli.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Involved with Parent-Teacher Associations and community-based organizations, Semivli argued there needed to be more focus on keeping kids out of gangs so that they are not “threatened into joining.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With the current debate on police salaries and the battle against MS-13, Semivli said she felt hopeful that the extra funding will be used in good faith. “Do I believe there is gang violence a problem on Long Island? Honestly, there is a problem for people of color being disenfranchised, where the children are forgotten by the government,” said Semivli. 
She added that the government should provide “positive peer mentoring and community projects to make all people feel safe.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To ease community relations, Suffolk County Police announced a list of community meetings leading up to June. Semivli pointed out that some of the meetings aren’t actually in their precincts. “I called up headquarters in Yaphank, and was told that each individual precinct decides where community meetings are held,” she said.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In minority communities, locations for the meetings were scheduled within the precincts. This was not the case for predominantly white communities like the First and Fourth precincts, where meetings are scheduled to take place in local libraries. Semivli argued the lack of policy is discriminatory.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When Cuomo first announced the anti-gang spending package on March 30, he claimed $16 million would go towards reaching at-risk youth. Two weeks later, on April 11, Cuomo announced an additional $2 million in the package to go towards aid for law enforcement on Long Island.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite historically low crime rates, Suffolk County Police Department is expecting additional funding in 2019. MS-13 violence on Long Island is an issue, however, Long Islanders like Semivli are unhappy with the amount of money spent on law enforcement. The governor’s office could not be reached for comment.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 03 May 2018 11:24:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/cuomo-gang-funding/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/cuomo-gang-funding/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Lessons in Being Left Behind: Public School Performance in our Nation’s Capital</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;With huge achievement gaps between schools and on average more than half of all students failing to meet literacy expectations on standardized tests, the D.C. public school system (DCPS) is struggling to get elementary school students reading at grade level. Despite improvements in literacy rates over time, low English language arts achievement persists. The numbers draw troubling connections between where a child grows up, the school they attend, and their future success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Experts say that fourth grade is the benchmark age at which students should be reading at grade level. However, according to the National Assessment of Educational Progress, “only about one-third of our nation’s fourth graders can read proficiently.” The numbers become more distressing in impoverished areas where the NAEP says only “20 percent of low-income students are reading proficiently” at this same age.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Washington, students’ reading, and math abilities are evaluated by PARCC (Partnership for Assessment of Readiness for College and Careers) an annual assessment for students grades three through eight on Common Core standards. The test measures skills like problem solving, critical thinking, and evidence-based reading.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/parc1.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/parc2.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;
&lt;img src=&quot;../images/parc3.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since PARCC’s first year, the number of students performing well on the reading section has risen incrementally, moving from 25 percent meeting or exceeding expectations in 2015 to 31 percent this past year. Yet, these increases may not mean much. According to Steven Bahr of the National Center for Education Statistics: “The average reading score for fourth-grade students in D.C. in 2017 was not significantly different from their average score in 2015 and was higher than the average score in 2002.” In 2002 the average literacy score in D.C. was 191, compared to the national average of 217, according to The Nation’s Report Card. Today, the average literacy score in D.C. is 213, compared to the national average of 221, a large increase from 2002. Bahr also added that “the average score of DCPS fourth-graders was not dissimilar to the average score for public school students in large cities” in 2017. Although DCPS is on par with other cities of its size, progress in literacy is not happening as quickly as people would like. Kaya Henderson, the former Chancellor of DC Public Schools at the time, called these results “sobering” considering the ways D.C. has left to go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/ela1.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though the percentages of students who are meeting or exceeding expectations is rising, the percentages of students at each respective proficiency level (1 being least proficient and 5 being most proficient) are staying relatively consistent, especially within the transitional reading levels: 2 and 3. Only Levels 4 and 1 appear to be undergoing somewhat significant shifts. This means students are moving out of the lowest level and into the highest achieving level, yet the majority of students are staying put in the “approaching expectations” categories.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/levels.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scores do not vary much by age, but they do fluctuate greatly depending on race and socioeconomic status. Test scores reveal the ways in which these factors are intertwined and how a child’s privilege and circumstances dictate a lot about their academic success. PARCC scores from 2016 to 2017 show that the highest performing racial group in DCPS is white students by a wide margin, followed closely by children of mixed race, Asian Americans, Hawaiian, and Pacific Islander and American Indian and Alaskan Natives in the equal percentages, Hispanic students, and lowest scoring: Black Americans. These alarming numbers highlight large gaps of almost 60 percent disparity between white students and students of color.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/raceschools.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The inequalities continue, as links between racial breakdowns and economic status are also reflected. The 2010 census of D.C. shows Wards 2, 3, and 4 are among the richest areas in the district with low poverty rates and average family incomes in the 100 and 200 thousand range. In contrast, Wards 7 and 8 have the highest rates of poverty (more than a quarter of their areas) and very low average family incomes hovering between 40 and 55 thousand, a sum often earned by one person per year. Wards 7 and 8’s black populations are also dominant, making up over 90 percent of these areas. While, richer Wards, although not entirely whitewashed, tend to have a sizeable portion of the population made up of white Americans.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/wards_race.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/wards_poverty.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Not only do race and economic status go hand in hand, but PARCC percentages correlate with these factors. The greatest number of students reaching the upper levels for literacy fall in Wards 2, 3, and 4. In Ward 3 schools, over 70 percent of students exceed standards and roughly 88 percent meet standards for PARCC. In sharp contrast, in Ward 8 schools, 37 percent of students meet literacy standards and only 14 percent exceed them. Students in the poorest Wards by consequence are placed on an unequal playing field to their wealthier peers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/wards_scatter.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the disparities are not apparent enough, we must note that in some schools within Wards 7 and 8, hardly any students are meeting reading standards. Ward 8’s Simon Elementary School and Hendley Elementary School only had 2 percent and 4 percent of students meet or exceed expectations. Ward 7’s CW Harris Elementary and Smothers Elementary similarly have only 5 percent and 6 percent of their students meet or exceed standards in literacy on the PARCC. If over 95 percent of students are leaving these elementary schools without basic grade level reading skills, what does it mean for these student’s future success?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Doubly concerning, many of the District’s schools fall within the poorest Wards, whereas the richer Wards tend to have fewer public schools available. Wealthy Wards 2 and 3, each have only 10 public schools in total. On the other hand, Ward 7 has 32 schools for public use and Ward 8 has 35. Part of this can be explained by the increased availability of private and charter schools within certain parts of D.C. Still, what does this say that so many students are receiving their education from these poor areas that statistically perform poorly on standardized tests?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/average_wards.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite less than desirable results, all hope isn’t yet lost. New initiatives and efforts are being made with each passing year to reverse the effects of poor literacy education within some schools inside DCPS and spur future progress. For one, DCPS has launched the teacher education program: LEAP that stands for Learning Together to Advance our Practice at every school, in every classroom, according to their 2016 press release. The program serves to strengthen teacher skills in teaching Common Core concepts through weekly development meetings run by education professionals like principals and administrators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading Partners is another initiative attempting to tackle the tricky issue of low literacy with the help of its 11,422 community volunteers. Focusing on reading skills, the children’s literacy nonprofit has a sizeable reach, serving 19 schools across Wards within the DCPS system. Some D.C. partners include Ward 8’s Aiton Elementary School and Malcolm X Elementary School and Ward 4’s Dorothy I. Height Elementary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The students the program serves tend to be of lower income levels, measured by 92 percent of Reading Partners students being on free or reduced lunch programs. Almost a third of students who participate in a program are also English language learners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/reading_partners.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With their help, Reading Partners boasts that “90 percent of K-2 students master key foundational reading skills needed to read at grade level” and “83 percent of all reading partner students met or exceeded their primary end of the year literacy goal” as of 2017. Katie Nicolle, a site Manager for Reading Partner’s Dorothy I. Height Elementary School, says it well when she explains: “we focus on doing one thing very well. We tutor Kindergarten through Fourth Graders, that are one month to two and half years behind in reading and are not qualified to receive other special reading services.” She goes on to say another “unquantified benefit from Reading Partners is the education it gives to our community members. Many of our tutors are voters or future voters in the community. They can witness the passion and drive of educators. They can see how systems of oppression have affected some students over others.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;../images/readingpartners.png&quot; alt=&quot;alt text&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The district, through its constant program revamping, clearly is putting in the work to get students where they need to be. The progress is slow, but educator, Katie Nicolle assures us “every year we work to get better at what we do. Education is so dynamic, and it requires educators to adapt, change, and improve. We are not complicit.”&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 02 May 2018 19:05:00 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/dc-school-performance/</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://andrewbtran.github.io/au-spring-18/au-spring-18/dc-school-performance/</guid>
        
        
        <category>one</category>
        
        <category>two</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
